<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://dinoarla.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://dinoarla.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-02-02T05:18:58+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Notes of a dedication | Dino Arla</title><subtitle>Dino Arla is an Electrical Engineer at PLN. Graduate student of MMT ITS. Corporate Innovator Winner. Machine Learning &amp; AI Enthusiast. Full Stack Web Developer. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Companions of PLN in Power Generation - Now Become a Proud Husbands and Fatherman</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/friendship/2023/07/22/companion-pln.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Companions of PLN in Power Generation - Now Become a Proud Husbands and Fatherman"/><published>2023-07-22T23:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-22T23:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/friendship/2023/07/22/companion-pln</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/friendship/2023/07/22/companion-pln.html"><![CDATA[<p>In the ever-evolving world of power generation, a group of young, spirited individuals embarked on a journey that would not only shape their careers but also their personal lives. These companions from PLN (Perusahaan Listrik Negara), Indonesia’s state electricity company, have grown together professionally and personally, transitioning from being fresh graduates to seasoned professionals, and now, loving husbands and proud fathers.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> The Companions of PLN in Power Generation </div> <h2 id="the-beginnings">The Beginnings</h2> <p>The story of these comrades began in the bustling halls of PLN, where they met as new recruits eager to make a mark in the field of power generation. Their shared mission to ensure reliable electricity supply to millions of Indonesians forged a bond that transcended professional boundaries. Late-night shifts, challenging projects, and countless brainstorming sessions were the backdrop to their budding camaraderie.</p> <h2 id="the-journey-in-power-generation">The Journey in Power Generation</h2> <p>Working in power generation is no small feat. It demands technical expertise, resilience, and a commitment to continuous learning. These companions quickly adapted to the dynamic environment, supporting each other through the complexities of the job. They celebrated successes and consoled one another in the face of setbacks, learning invaluable lessons along the way.</p> <h2 id="from-colleagues-to-friends">From Colleagues to Friends</h2> <p>As time passed, their relationships deepened. What started as professional collaboration blossomed into genuine friendships. They shared not only career aspirations but also personal dreams and challenges. Weekend get-togethers became a norm, and soon, they were an integral part of each other’s lives outside of work.</p> <h2 id="the-next-chapter-marriage-and-parenthood">The Next Chapter: Marriage and Parenthood</h2> <p>Life took a beautiful turn when these companions found love and embarked on the journey of marriage. Their weddings were joyous occasions, attended by their PLN colleagues who had become more like family. As they transitioned into married life, they continued to support each other, now sharing advice on balancing work and personal responsibilities.</p> <p>The arrival of children marked another milestone in their lives. Parenthood brought its own set of challenges and joys, and these friends found new ways to connect, swapping stories about sleepless nights and first steps. They cherished the opportunity to watch their children grow, hopeful for a future where they could share the tales of their enduring friendship and professional journey.</p> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>Today, these companions of PLN, who once embarked on a journey in power generation, stand as exemplars of balance and perseverance. They have shown that it is possible to nurture both a successful career and a fulfilling family life. Their story is a testament to the power of friendship, unity, and shared experiences, reminding us that while the path to success is important, it is the companions we travel with that truly enrich our lives.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="friendship"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[These companions from PLN (Perusahaan Listrik Negara), Indonesia's state electricity company, have grown together professionally and personally, transitioning from being fresh graduates to seasoned professionals, and now, loving husbands and proud fathers.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Togetherness with the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/06/15/cikedung-p2tl.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Togetherness with the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team"/><published>2023-06-15T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-15T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/06/15/cikedung-p2tl</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/06/15/cikedung-p2tl.html"><![CDATA[<p>In the quaint district of Cikedung, a remarkable team of dedicated individuals is making a significant difference in the community. Led by the dynamic Dino Arla, who serves as the Commander of Energy Transactions, the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team works tirelessly to ensure that electricity usage in the area is both efficient and fair. But beyond their professional commitments, there exists a strong sense of camaraderie and togetherness among the team members that sets them apart.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-04-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-04-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-04-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-04.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team </div> <h2 id="fostering-a-family-like-atmosphere">Fostering a Family-Like Atmosphere</h2> <p>Under Dino Arla’s leadership, every individual in the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team is valued not only for their skills and contributions but also for their unique personalities. Dino has instilled a culture that fosters an environment more like a family than a workplace. Regular team-building activities, such as community outings and participation in local events, help strengthen the bonds between members. Through these activities, team members learn to trust and rely on each other, which is crucial in their line of work.</p> <h2 id="bringing-the-community-together">Bringing the Community Together</h2> <p>The PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team, guided by Dino’s strategic vision, is deeply integrated into the community. They actively engage with locals to educate them about electricity usage and safety. These interactions are not just formalities but are opportunities for the team to connect with residents on a personal level. This approach, championed by Dino, has created a strong rapport between the team and the community, making their enforcement efforts more effective and welcomed.</p> <h2 id="overcoming-challenges-together">Overcoming Challenges Together</h2> <p>The job of ensuring proper electricity usage is not without its challenges. Under Dino Arla’s capable supervision, the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team often faces difficult situations, such as dealing with illegal electricity connections or addressing power shortages. However, the sense of unity among the team members allows them to face these challenges head-on. They support each other through thick and thin, celebrating successes and learning from setbacks together.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-03-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-03-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-03-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-03.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team - Meeting and Evaluation </div> <h2 id="significant-financial-impact">Significant Financial Impact</h2> <p>The dedication and efficiency of the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team have significantly contributed to the recovery and saving of company income, exceeding 4 billion rupiahs. This remarkable achievement underscores the team’s effectiveness in combating electricity misuse and optimizing energy distribution.</p> <h2 id="the-impact-of-togetherness">The Impact of Togetherness</h2> <p>The togetherness of the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team, led by Dino Arla, has had a profound impact on both their work and their lives. It has improved their effectiveness in ensuring proper electricity usage and has contributed to a positive work environment that prioritizes well-being and collaboration. This unity, cultivated by Dino, is reflected in their interactions with the community and is a key factor in the team’s success.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-05-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-05-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-05-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-05.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-06-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-06-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-06-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-06.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-07-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-07-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-07-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-07.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team </div> <p>In conclusion, with Dino Arla at the helm, the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team stands as a model of how teamwork and togetherness can lead to success and satisfaction in professional endeavors. Their dedication to their work and each other is a testament to the power of unity and community spirit.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="pln"/><category term="cikedung"/><category term="indramayu"/><category term="acceleraterenewableenergy"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Led by the dynamic Dino Arla, who serves as the Commander of Energy Transactions, the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team works tirelessly to ensure that electricity usage in the area is both efficient and fair.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Enhancing Customer Experience - PLN Cikedung’s Service Connection Team</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/06/14/cikedung-yanbung.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Enhancing Customer Experience - PLN Cikedung’s Service Connection Team"/><published>2023-06-14T15:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-14T15:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/06/14/cikedung-yanbung</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/06/14/cikedung-yanbung.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2> <p>The utility sector is a crucial backbone of modern society, providing essential services that power our homes, businesses, and industries. In Indonesia, PLN (Perusahaan Listrik Negara) plays a vital role in ensuring that electricity reaches every corner of the country. Today, we’re taking a closer look at the “Tim Pelayanan Penyambungan” or “Service Connection Team” in Cikedung, a dedicated unit that has been making significant strides in improving customer experience and satisfaction.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> PLN Cikedung Service Connection Team </div> <h2 id="who-is-the-service-connection-team">Who is the Service Connection Team?</h2> <p>The Service Connection Team of PLN Cikedung is a specialized group of skilled professionals responsible for overseeing and executing the process of connecting new electricity installations. This team manages everything from initial customer inquiries to the final installation, ensuring a seamless experience for customers who need to connect to the power grid.</p> <h2 id="key-functions-of-the-team">Key Functions of the Team</h2> <ol> <li>Customer Consultation and Support</li> <li>The team serves as the first point of contact for customers looking to connect their premises to the electricity supply. They provide comprehensive consultations, offering guidance on the application process, required documentation, and any relevant regulations or tariffs.</li> <li>Site Assessment and Planning</li> <li>Before installation, the team conducts thorough site assessments to determine the specific requirements for each connection. This involves evaluating the infrastructure, identifying potential challenges, and developing a tailored plan to ensure a smooth and efficient installation process.</li> <li>Installation and Quality Assurance</li> <li>Once the planning phase is complete, the team proceeds with the installation. Using state-of-the-art equipment and adhering to strict safety standards, they ensure that all connections are made accurately and securely. After installation, they perform rigorous quality checks to confirm that the service meets all operational and safety standards.</li> </ol> <h2 id="commitment-to-customer-satisfaction">Commitment to Customer Satisfaction</h2> <p>One of the standout attributes of the Service Connection Team is their unwavering commitment to customer satisfaction. They prioritize clear communication and responsiveness, keeping customers informed at every stage of the process and addressing any concerns promptly. Their customer-centric approach has earned them a reputation for reliability and trustworthiness in the Cikedung area.</p> <h2 id="challenges-and-innovations">Challenges and Innovations</h2> <p>Like any service-oriented team, the PLN Cikedung Service Connection Team faces challenges, such as navigating complex field environments and managing high customer demands. However, they continually strive to innovate and improve their processes. By leveraging technology, such as digital platforms for tracking and managing customer data, they enhance efficiency and accuracy in service delivery.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-03-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-03-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-03-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-03.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> PLN Cikedung Service Connection Team </div> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>The PLN Cikedung Service Connection Team exemplifies dedication and innovation in the electricity sector. By focusing on customer needs and embracing modern technology, they not only improve connectivity but also contribute to the broader goal of electrifying every corner of Indonesia. Their work ensures that communities and businesses can thrive with reliable and efficient access to electricity, powering progress and development in the region.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="pln"/><category term="cikedung"/><category term="indramayu"/><category term="acceleraterenewableenergy"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we’re taking a closer look at the Tim Pelayanan Penyambungan or Service Connection Team in PLN Cikedung, a dedicated unit that has been making significant strides in improving customer experience and satisfaction.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcoming Our New Manager at PLN Cikedung - A new era of teamwork, sustainability, and innovation</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/06/10/cikedung-new-manager.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcoming Our New Manager at PLN Cikedung - A new era of teamwork, sustainability, and innovation"/><published>2023-06-10T14:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-10T14:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/06/10/cikedung-new-manager</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/06/10/cikedung-new-manager.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are thrilled to announce a fresh chapter in our journey at PLN Cikedung with the appointment of our new Manager and Leader, Lukman Ismail. As of June 2023, Lukman Ismail will be spearheading our operations, bringing a wealth of knowledge and experience to our team.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/05-new-manager/dino-arla-ckd-manager-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/05-new-manager/dino-arla-ckd-manager-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/05-new-manager/dino-arla-ckd-manager-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/05-new-manager/dino-arla-ckd-manager-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/05-new-manager/dino-arla-ckd-manager-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/05-new-manager/dino-arla-ckd-manager-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/05-new-manager/dino-arla-ckd-manager-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/05-new-manager/dino-arla-ckd-manager-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> PLN Cikedung New Squad of June 2023 </div> <h2 id="a-brief-history-of-pln-cikedung">A Brief History of PLN Cikedung</h2> <p>PLN Cikedung has been a cornerstone in the energy sector since its establishment in 2019. Over the years, we have evolved to become one of the leading power distribution companies in the region, renowned for our commitment to providing reliable and sustainable energy solutions.</p> <p>Our journey began with a modest start, serving a small community and steadily growing our infrastructure and capacity. With a focus on innovation and customer service, PLN Cikedung expanded its reach and capabilities, integrating advanced technologies that set new standards in power distribution and management.</p> <h2 id="a-new-era-of-leadership">A New Era of Leadership</h2> <p>Lukman Ismail joins us with over 15 years of experience in the energy sector, specializing in technical of energy distribution. His previous roles include supervisor of technical both ULP and UP3, where he successfully led projects that improved operational efficiency and customer satisfaction.</p> <p>His proven track record in leadership and innovation makes him an ideal fit for PLN Cikedung. Lukman Ismail is committed to driving our company forward, embracing new opportunities, and tackling challenges with a strategic and visionary approach.</p> <h2 id="vision-for-pln-cikedung">Vision for PLN Cikedung</h2> <p>In his inaugural address, Lukman Ismail emphasized the importance of teamwork, sustainability, and innovation. His vision for PLN Cikedung is centered around enhancing our service quality, expanding our renewable energy capabilities, and fostering a culture of continuous improvement.</p> <p>Under Lukman Ismail’s leadership, we are excited to explore new technologies and methodologies that align with the global shift towards sustainable energy solutions. His focus on employee development and community engagement ensures that PLN Cikedung not only meets but exceeds the expectations of our stakeholders.</p> <h2 id="looking-ahead">Looking Ahead</h2> <p>The future is bright at PLN Cikedung, and we are confident that with Lukman Ismail at the helm, we will achieve new milestones and set benchmarks in the industry. We invite all our partners, employees, and customers to join us in welcoming Lukman Ismail and to look forward to what promises to be an exciting and transformative era for our organization.</p> <p>Stay tuned for more updates and initiatives as we embark on this new journey together. Welcome aboard, Lukman Ismail!</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="pln"/><category term="cikedung"/><category term="indramayu"/><category term="acceleraterenewableenergy"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are thrilled to announce a fresh chapter in our journey at PLN Cikedung with the appointment of our new Manager and Leader, Lukman Ismail. As of June 2023, Lukman Ismail will be spearheading our operations, bringing a wealth of knowledge and experience to our team.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PLN Cikedung Squad Year 2023 - A Year of Power and Progress</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/05/10/cikedung-squad.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PLN Cikedung Squad Year 2023 - A Year of Power and Progress"/><published>2023-05-10T12:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-10T12:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/05/10/cikedung-squad</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/05/10/cikedung-squad.html"><![CDATA[<p>The year 2023 has been a remarkable one for the PLN Cikedung squad, a dedicated unit of the State Electricity Company of Indonesia (PLN) located in Indramayu. With the responsibility of serving over 70,000 customers, they have shown exceptional commitment and innovation in meeting the community’s electricity needs.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> PLN Cikedung Squad Year 2023 </div> <h2 id="customer-centric-focus">Customer-Centric Focus</h2> <p>The PLN Cikedung squad has always prioritized customer satisfaction. This year, they have implemented several initiatives to enhance customer service, including the introduction of a new online portal that allows customers to report outages and pay bills conveniently. These improvements have not only increased efficiency but also strengthened the trust between PLN Cikedung and its customers.</p> <h2 id="technological-advancements">Technological Advancements</h2> <p>In 2023, the Cikedung team embraced technological advancements to improve the reliability and efficiency of their services. With the integration of smart grid technology, the squad has been able to better manage electricity distribution, quickly responding to demand fluctuations and minimizing power outages. This transition has paved the way for more sustainable and reliable power solutions.</p> <h2 id="community-engagement">Community Engagement</h2> <p>Understanding the importance of community involvement, PLN Cikedung has engaged in various community outreach programs. These initiatives aimed at educating the public about energy conservation and safety have received positive feedback. By fostering a sense of community responsibility, PLN Cikedung has helped promote sustainable energy practices among its customer base.</p> <h2 id="environmental-responsibility">Environmental Responsibility</h2> <p>With a growing emphasis on sustainability, the PLN Cikedung squad has also been committed to reducing their environmental footprint. Through initiatives such as integrating renewable energy sources and promoting energy efficiency, they are not only contributing to a greener planet but also setting an example for others in the industry.</p> <h2 id="challenges-and-triumphs">Challenges and Triumphs</h2> <p>Despite facing challenges such as infrastructure demands and increasing energy consumption, the PLN Cikedung squad has demonstrated resilience and adaptability. Their ability to overcome obstacles and deliver on their promises has been a testament to their dedication and hard work.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-03-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-03-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-03-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-03.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> PLN Cikedung Squad Year 2023 </div> <p>In conclusion, the year 2023 has been a transformative year for the PLN Cikedung squad. Through innovation, dedication, and community engagement, they have not only upheld their reputation but also set new benchmarks for the future. As they move forward, the PLN Cikedung squad continues to be a beacon of progress in the field of electricity distribution, serving as a powerful example for others to follow.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="pln"/><category term="cikedung"/><category term="indramayu"/><category term="acceleraterenewableenergy"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The year 2023 has been a remarkable one for the PLN Cikedung squad, a dedicated unit of the State Electricity Company of Indonesia (PLN) located in Indramayu. With the responsibility of serving over 70,000 customers, they have shown exceptional commitment and innovation in meeting the community's electricity needs.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reuniting with Old Friends - PLN Batch 7 year 2013 (King Solomon) Gathering for Eid al-Fitr 1444 H</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/friendship/2023/04/27/reuniting-with-old-friends.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reuniting with Old Friends - PLN Batch 7 year 2013 (King Solomon) Gathering for Eid al-Fitr 1444 H"/><published>2023-04-27T12:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-27T12:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/friendship/2023/04/27/reuniting-with-old-friends</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/friendship/2023/04/27/reuniting-with-old-friends.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2> <p>Eid al-Fitr, a significant celebration for Muslims around the world, transcends religious rites, symbolizing unity, forgiveness, and the rekindling of relationships. This year, the spirit of Eid brought us together with our cherished friends from “PLN Batch 7 year 2013 (King Solomon)”, marking a joyful reunion filled with laughter and nostalgia.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Dino and his family celebrate Eid al-Fitr 1444 H with PLN Batch 7 year 2013 (King Solomon) </div> <h2 id="a-walk-down-memory-lane">A Walk Down Memory Lane</h2> <p>The gathering took place at the home of one of our colleagues, a cozy haven that was soon filled with familiar faces and the warm embrace of friendship. As we reminisced about our formative years in PLN, it was incredible to see how far we have come since our days in the technical training program, affectionately known as “PLN Angkatan 7 Jalur Pelaksana”.</p> <p>The conversations flowed as freely as the delectable Eid treats. Stories of our early days in the field, the successes, the challenges, and the bonds we forged through hard work and shared experiences, were recounted with enthusiasm and fondness. Each tale told was a reminder of the journey we had embarked on together and the shared dreams we continue to pursue. Without realizing it, we have all now become parents.</p> <h2 id="parenting-moments">Parenting Moments</h2> <p>One of the most endearing highlights of the reunion was the presence of our children, who quickly became the stars of the event. As the adults caught up, the little ones mingled effortlessly, playing games and forming friendships of their own, a new generation of bonds taking shape. At one point, the living room was transformed into an impromptu play area, filled with laughter and the sounds of tiny footsteps running around.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-04-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-04-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-04-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-04.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Eid Al-Fitr parenting moments with PLN Batch 7 year 2013 (King Solomon) </div> <p>A particularly memorable moment was when two of the kids decided to host a “talent show,” showcasing their unique skills. Their enthusiasm and creativity left everyone in stitches and served as a charming reminder of the joys of parenthood we now share. Another touching scene unfolded when a child, eager to demonstrate their reading skills, gathered a small audience to listen. It was heartwarming to see the pride in their parents’ eyes, a universal moment every parent cherishes.</p> <h2 id="unity-and-gratitude">Unity and Gratitude</h2> <p>In addition to reliving past memories, the gathering was an opportunity to express gratitude for the support and camaraderie that have helped us navigate our careers and personal lives. It was a time to acknowledge the growth and achievements of our peers, celebrate our shared heritage, and strengthen the bonds that unite us.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-03-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-03-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-03-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-03.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Togetherness of King Solomon Founders </div> <h2 id="looking-forward">Looking Forward</h2> <p>As we look to the future, the reunion reminded us of the importance of maintaining relationships and the powerful impact they have on our lives. We left with a renewed sense of connection and the promise to meet again, ensuring that the spirit of “Silaturahmi” continues to thrive within our PLN family.</p> <p>Eid al-Fitr 1444 H has been a truly enriching experience, one that reinforced the value of friendship and community, and highlighted the enduring strength of our bonds. We are grateful for the memories shared, and eagerly look forward to creating new ones in the years to come.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="friendship"/><category term="personal"/><category term="friendship"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This year, the spirit of Eid brought us together with our cherished friends from PLN Batch 7 year 2013 (King Solomon), marking a joyful reunion filled with laughter and nostalgia.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Happy Eid al-Fitr - Victory Shines, Bringing a Fresh Energy to a New Day</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/family/2023/04/22/happy-eid-al-fitr.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Happy Eid al-Fitr - Victory Shines, Bringing a Fresh Energy to a New Day"/><published>2023-04-22T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-22T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/family/2023/04/22/happy-eid-al-fitr</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/family/2023/04/22/happy-eid-al-fitr.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2> <p>Hari Raya Idul Fitri, also known as Eid al-Fitr, is a significant celebration for Muslims around the world. Celebrated on 1 Syawal 1444 H / April 22, 2023 M, this day marks the end of Ramadan, a holy month of fasting, prayer, and reflection. Known as a festival of breaking the fast, Eid al-Fitr signifies a time of joy and celebration after a month of spiritual rejuvenation and self-discipline.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/01-happy-eid/dino-arla-happy-eid-2023-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/01-happy-eid/dino-arla-happy-eid-2023-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/01-happy-eid/dino-arla-happy-eid-2023-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/01-happy-eid/dino-arla-happy-eid-2023-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/01-happy-eid/dino-arla-happy-eid-2023-03-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/01-happy-eid/dino-arla-happy-eid-2023-03-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/01-happy-eid/dino-arla-happy-eid-2023-03-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/01-happy-eid/dino-arla-happy-eid-2023-03.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Dino and his family celebrate Eid al-Fitr 1444 H - April 22, 2023 </div> <h2 id="the-spirit-of-victory">The Spirit of Victory</h2> <p>Eid al-Fitr is often referred to as “Kemenangan Hadir Menyinari Jiwa” which translates to “Victory Shines on the Soul.” This victory is not only about the resilience and strength to fast for a month but also about the spiritual triumph achieved through personal growth and the purifying of one’s soul. It is a time to reflect on the virtues of patience, humility, and gratitude cultivated during Ramadan.</p> <h2 id="a-fresh-start">A Fresh Start</h2> <p>The celebration of Eid al-Fitr brings about a feeling of renewal and a fresh start, symbolized by the phrase “Berikan Energi Bersih di Hari yang Baru” or “Bring Fresh Energy to the New Day.” It is a time to let go of past grievances and embrace a future filled with positivity and goodwill. Families and communities come together, bridging gaps and strengthening bonds.</p> <h2 id="traditions-and-celebrations">Traditions and Celebrations</h2> <p>The day begins with the special Eid prayer performed in congregation, often held in large open areas or mosques. This is followed by a sermon that reminds individuals of their religious duties and the importance of maintaining the virtues practiced during Ramadan.</p> <p>One of the most cherished traditions of Eid al-Fitr is the act of giving, known as Zakat al-Fitr. This is a form of almsgiving given to the poor, ensuring that everyone can join in the celebrations. It serves as a reminder of the importance of charity and compassion in Islam.</p> <p>Families prepare special meals, don new clothes, and decorate their homes to mark the joyous occasion. A special dish, often sweets and festive meals, is prepared to share with family, friends, and neighbors. It’s a time for forgiveness, where people visit each other, exchange gifts, and ask for forgiveness for any wrongdoings.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/01-happy-eid/dino-arla-happy-eid-2023-04-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/01-happy-eid/dino-arla-happy-eid-2023-04-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/01-happy-eid/dino-arla-happy-eid-2023-04-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/01-happy-eid/dino-arla-happy-eid-2023-04.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Happy Eid al-Fitr 1444 H - April 22, 2023 </div> <h2 id="personal-reflections-and-experiences">Personal Reflections and Experiences</h2> <p>As a personal reflection, Hari Raya Idul Fitri has always been a profoundly meaningful time in my life. Growing up, it was not just a day of celebration but a reminder of the values instilled in me by my family and community. I vividly recall waking up early to join my family and neighbors for the Eid prayer, feeling a sense of unity and shared faith.</p> <p>The anticipation of visiting relatives and friends, exchanging warm greetings, and indulging in delicious traditional foods added to the festivity. I remember helping my mother prepare special dishes like rendang and ketupat, which filled our home with tantalizing aromas.</p> <p>The sharing of meals and laughter with loved ones has always been the highlight of the day. It is a time when past misunderstandings are forgiven, strengthening the bond and fostering a spirit of togetherness. These gatherings remind me of the blessings of friendship and family, and the importance of compassion and empathy.</p> <h2 id="global-aspects-of-eid-al-fitr-celebrations">Global Aspects of Eid al-Fitr Celebrations</h2> <p>Eid al-Fitr is celebrated globally, with each region bringing its unique customs and traditions to the festivities. In the Middle East, large family gatherings and feasts are common, with cultural dishes like dates and lamb being popular. Many people visit the graves of their loved ones to offer prayers and remember those who have passed.</p> <p>In Southeast Asia, particularly in Indonesia and Malaysia, the celebration involves visiting friends and relatives, and the exchange of “duit raya” or money packets is a cherished tradition. Traditional foods such as ketupat, lemang, and rendang are commonly served.</p> <p>In South Asia, especially in countries like Pakistan, India, and Bangladesh, the day is marked with vibrant colors and festive clothing. Henna designs and bangles are popular among women, and sweet dishes such as sheer khurma and jalebi are enjoyed.</p> <p>In Western countries, Muslims often gather at community centers and mosques to celebrate Eid together, sharing meals and connecting with each other. Despite the cultural differences, the underlying essence of Eid al-Fitr remains the same worldwide: a celebration of faith, gratitude, and community.</p> <h2 id="celebrating-in-pontianak-city-west-kalimantan">Celebrating in Pontianak City, West Kalimantan</h2> <p>In Pontianak City, West Kalimantan, Hari Raya Idul Fitri is celebrated with great enthusiasm and warmth. Dino Arla, a resident of Pontianak, looks forward to this special occasion every year, as it brings together his large family under one roof. The day begins with Dino and his family attending the early morning Eid prayer at the mosque, joining the community in a moment of spiritual reflection and gratitude.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/01-happy-eid/dino-arla-happy-eid-2023-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/01-happy-eid/dino-arla-happy-eid-2023-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/01-happy-eid/dino-arla-happy-eid-2023-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/01-happy-eid/dino-arla-happy-eid-2023-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Dino's family celebrate Eid al-Fitr 1444 H - April 22, 2023 </div> <p>Upon returning home, the family gathers for a festive meal, sharing traditional dishes such as opor ayam and lemang. The aroma of these delicious foods fills the air, adding to the joyous atmosphere. Dino cherishes these moments of togetherness, as they provide an opportunity to reconnect with family members and strengthen familial bonds.</p> <p>As the day progresses, Dino and his family visit relatives and friends, exchanging greetings and gifts. The exchange of “duit raya” among the younger members of the family adds a touch of excitement and happiness. Each visit is accompanied by laughter and stories, creating lasting memories for Dino and his loved ones.</p> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>Hari Raya Idul Fitri is a celebration of spiritual victory and renewal. It brings a sense of joy and unity, as communities come together to celebrate their faith and the virtues strengthened during Ramadan. It is a festival that illuminates the soul with a fresh and positive energy, setting the tone for the days to come. As we celebrate this auspicious occasion, let us embrace the values of compassion, charity, and unity, carrying them forward into a bright and hopeful future.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="family"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hari Raya Idul Fitri, also known as Eid al-Fitr, is a significant celebration for Muslims around the world. Celebrated on 1 Syawal 1444 H / April 22, 2023 M, this day marks the end of Ramadan, a holy month of fasting, prayer, and reflection]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mudik During Eid al-Fitr 1444 H - A Heartwarming Tradition</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/family/2023/04/15/mudik.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mudik During Eid al-Fitr 1444 H - A Heartwarming Tradition"/><published>2023-04-15T13:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-15T13:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/family/2023/04/15/mudik</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/family/2023/04/15/mudik.html"><![CDATA[<p>Every year, millions of people across Indonesia embark on a heartwarming journey known as “mudik” to return to their hometowns and villages to celebrate Eid al-Fitr with their families. This annual tradition, coinciding with the end of Ramadan, is a time of joy, reflection, and reunion. In 1444 H, mudik continues to hold deep cultural significance, bringing together family members who have been separated by distance and time.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/03-mudik/dino-arla-mudik-03-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/03-mudik/dino-arla-mudik-03-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/03-mudik/dino-arla-mudik-03-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/03-mudik/dino-arla-mudik-03.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Sitting on the plane prepare to meet whole family member </div> <h2 id="the-significance-of-mudik">The Significance of Mudik</h2> <p>Mudik, derived from the Javanese word “mulih” which means “to return home”, is an annual pilgrimage that many Indonesians undertake to reconnect with their roots. This journey symbolizes the return to one’s origins and the importance of family and togetherness. It is a time when people from all walks of life, regardless of age, profession, or societal status, make their way back to their beloved hometowns.</p> <h2 id="preparations-and-challenges">Preparations and Challenges</h2> <p>Planning for mudik requires meticulous preparation. Families often book their travel weeks or even months in advance to secure transportation, whether by train, bus, car, or plane. This massive movement of people creates a festive yet challenging period for travelers, as roads, airports, and train stations become crowded.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/03-mudik/dino-arla-mudik-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/03-mudik/dino-arla-mudik-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/03-mudik/dino-arla-mudik-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/03-mudik/dino-arla-mudik-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> A situation on the airport during mudik Eid al-Fitr 1444 H </div> <p>Despite potential challenges such as traffic congestion and delays, the enthusiasm for mudik remains undiminished. The anticipation of reuniting with loved ones and celebrating Eid al-Fitr together overshadows the inconveniences. Many travelers see it as an adventure and an opportunity to create lasting memories.</p> <h2 id="dino-arlas-mudik-journey">Dino Arla’s Mudik Journey</h2> <p>One such traveler, Dino Arla, embarked on a remarkable mudik journey from Indramayu to Pontianak. His trip, involving both train and plane travel, exemplifies the determination and love for family that characterizes the mudik tradition.</p> <p>Dino began his journey by boarding a train from Indramayu, a town known for its rich cultural heritage. The train ride offered scenic views of Java’s landscape, providing a moment of tranquility before the bustling activity of airports.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/03-mudik/dino-arla-mudik-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/03-mudik/dino-arla-mudik-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/03-mudik/dino-arla-mudik-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/03-mudik/dino-arla-mudik-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/03-mudik/dino-arla-mudik-04-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/03-mudik/dino-arla-mudik-04-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/03-mudik/dino-arla-mudik-04-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/03-mudik/dino-arla-mudik-04.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Dino trip by using train and plane travel </div> <p>Upon arriving at the airport, Dino took a flight to Pontianak, a city located on the island of Borneo. The flight, though short, was filled with excitement and the anticipation of reuniting with his family. Dino’s journey is a testament to the lengths people will go to maintain familial connections and uphold cherished traditions.</p> <h2 id="cultural-and-emotional-aspects">Cultural and Emotional Aspects</h2> <p>Mudik is not just a physical journey; it is an emotional and cultural one. It is a time to pause and appreciate the connections that bind families and communities together. As families gather to share meals and stories, they also engage in traditional practices, such as visiting the graves of ancestors and participating in communal prayers.</p> <p>For many, mudik is a chance to introduce younger generations to their heritage and instill in them the values of togetherness and gratitude. It is a moment to reflect on one’s origins and to express thankfulness for the blessings of life.</p> <h2 id="the-joy-of-reunion">The Joy of Reunion</h2> <p>The highlight of mudik is the joyous reunion with family members. After long journeys, travelers are greeted with warm embraces, laughter, and the aroma of traditional dishes prepared with love. It is a time for storytelling, reminiscing, and creating new memories.</p> <p>Families indulge in special Eid feasts, including delicacies like ketupat, rendang, and various traditional sweets. The air is filled with the sounds of children playing and the exchange of greetings and well-wishes.</p> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>Mudik during Eid al-Fitr 1444 H is more than just a travel ritual; it is a profound expression of cultural heritage and familial love. As millions embark on their journeys back home, the spirit of mudik continues to unite hearts and strengthen bonds, reminding us all of the importance of family and the joy of togetherness.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="family"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every year, millions of people across Indonesia embark on a heartwarming journey known as mudik to return to their hometowns and villages to celebrate Eid al-Fitr with their families. This annual tradition, coinciding with the end of Ramadan, is a time of joy, reflection, and reunion. In 1444 H, mudik continues to hold deep cultural significance, bringing together family members who have been separated by distance and time.]]></summary></entry></feed>