<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://dinoarla.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://dinoarla.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2026-02-03T08:39:08+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Notes of a dedication | Dino Arla</title><subtitle>Dino Arla is an Electrical Engineer at PLN. Graduate student of MMT ITS. Corporate Innovator Winner. Machine Learning &amp; AI Enthusiast. Full Stack Web Developer. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Signing of the Management Commitment at PLN Cikedung on the Anti-Bribery Management System (ABMS)</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/10/19/abms.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Signing of the Management Commitment at PLN Cikedung on the Anti-Bribery Management System (ABMS)"/><published>2023-10-19T13:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-19T13:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/10/19/abms</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/10/19/abms.html"><![CDATA[<p>On a remarkable day at the PLN Cikedung Branch Office, a significant milestone was achieved as the management gathered to sign the commitment towards implementing the Anti-Bribery Management System (ABMS). This event marks a pivotal step in reinforcing the ethical foundation and promoting transparency within the organization.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/17-abms/dino-arla-abms-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/17-abms/dino-arla-abms-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/17-abms/dino-arla-abms-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/17-abms/dino-arla-abms-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Signing of the Management Commitment at PLN Cikedung on the Anti-Bribery Management System (ABMS) </div> <h2 id="the-importance-of-abms">The Importance of ABMS</h2> <p>The Anti-Bribery Management System (ABMS) is a comprehensive framework designed to assist organizations in preventing, detecting, and responding to bribery. It supports a culture of integrity, transparency, and compliance with relevant anti-bribery laws. By adopting ABMS, PLN Cikedung demonstrates its dedication to upholding the highest standards of ethical conduct and corporate governance.</p> <h2 id="the-signing-ceremony">The Signing Ceremony</h2> <p>The signing ceremony was attended by key leaders and stakeholders at PLN Cikedung, including the branch manager, department heads, and other management team members. This gathering was an affirmation of their collective commitment to integrating the principles of ABMS into their daily operations.</p> <p>In his opening remarks, the branch manager emphasized the critical role that each employee plays in maintaining the integrity of the organization. He highlighted the importance of the ABMS commitment not only as a regulatory compliance measure but as a step towards fostering a culture where ethical behavior is a top priority.</p> <h2 id="moving-forward">Moving Forward</h2> <p>With the signing of this commitment, PLN Cikedung is poised to implement a series of measures aimed at ensuring compliance with the ABMS. These measures will include comprehensive training sessions for employees, the establishment of clear reporting mechanisms for unethical practices, and periodic audits to assess the effectiveness of the system.</p> <p>Furthermore, by adopting ABMS, PLN Cikedung aims to strengthen trust with its stakeholders, including customers, suppliers, and regulatory bodies. This initiative reflects the company’s proactive approach to mitigating risks associated with bribery and corruption, ensuring long-term sustainability and success.</p> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>The signing of the management commitment at PLN Cikedung for the Anti-Bribery Management System is more than just a formal procedure—it’s a testament to the organization’s dedication to ethical business practices. As the implementation progresses, PLN Cikedung is set to pave the way for a more transparent and accountable enterprise, setting a benchmark for others in the industry.</p> <p>This initiative reiterates that ethical business practices are at the heart of PLN Cikedung’s operations, promising a future of integrity and trustworthiness.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="pln"/><category term="pln"/><category term="cikedung"/><category term="indramayu"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On a remarkable day at the PLN Cikedung Branch Office, a significant milestone was achieved as the management gathered to sign the commitment towards implementing the Anti-Bribery Management System (ABMS). This event marks a pivotal step in reinforcing the ethical foundation and promoting transparency within the organization.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Revolutionizing Rice Milling in Cikedung - Same Day Service Activation for PT Pare Hade 3 by PLN</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/10/12/pare-hade.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Revolutionizing Rice Milling in Cikedung - Same Day Service Activation for PT Pare Hade 3 by PLN"/><published>2023-10-12T15:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-12T15:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/10/12/pare-hade</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/10/12/pare-hade.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="empowering-the-heartbeat-of-national-rice-production-with-reliable-197-kva-electricity">Empowering the Heartbeat of National Rice Production with Reliable 197 kVA Electricity</h2> <p>Nestled in the productive precincts of Indramayu, Cikedung stands proudly as a national rice granary, a title it has earned through years of dedicated cultivation and production. As technology continues to enhance agricultural processes, the importance of reliable electricity to power essential machinery cannot be overstated. This is where PLN Cikedung steps in, ensuring that the wheels of rice milling operations spin without interruption.</p> <p>Recently, PLN Cikedung embarked on a mission to deliver same-day service activation for PT Pare Hade 3, providing a robust 197 kVA power supply. This initiative is crucial as it fuels the heuler machines tasked with rice milling in the bountiful fields of Cikedung.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/16-pare-hade/dino-arla-pare-hade-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/16-pare-hade/dino-arla-pare-hade-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/16-pare-hade/dino-arla-pare-hade-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/16-pare-hade/dino-arla-pare-hade-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/16-pare-hade/dino-arla-pare-hade-03-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/16-pare-hade/dino-arla-pare-hade-03-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/16-pare-hade/dino-arla-pare-hade-03-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/16-pare-hade/dino-arla-pare-hade-03.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Same Day Service Activation for PT Pare Hade 3 by PLN </div> <h2 id="the-role-of-pln-in-powering-cikedung">The Role of PLN in Powering Cikedung</h2> <p>PLN Cikedung’s commitment to supporting local industries is evident in their rapid response and service delivery. By activating the electrical supply on the same day, PLN not only accelerates industrial progress but also supports the local economy. This service ensures that the rice milling machines operate smoothly, contributing to the national supply of rice.</p> <h2 id="ensuring-reliability-and-transparency-a-supervisors-perspective">Ensuring Reliability and Transparency: A Supervisor’s Perspective</h2> <p>At the helm of ensuring seamless energy transactions is Dino, the supervisor overseeing the energy transaction process. Dino’s role is pivotal in managing the installation and operation of the Metering and Limiting Equipment (Alat Pengukur dan Pembatas). His focus on reliability and transparency ensures that every step of the installation process meets the highest standards.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/16-pare-hade/dino-arla-pare-hade-05-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/16-pare-hade/dino-arla-pare-hade-05-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/16-pare-hade/dino-arla-pare-hade-05-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/16-pare-hade/dino-arla-pare-hade-05.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Electrical Panel of Pare Hade </div> <p>“Our goal is to make sure that PLN’s services are not just fast but also reliable,” Dino explains. “By maintaining transparency, we build trust with our clients, ensuring that all material processes are conducted with utmost integrity.”</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/16-pare-hade/dino-arla-pare-hade-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/16-pare-hade/dino-arla-pare-hade-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/16-pare-hade/dino-arla-pare-hade-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/16-pare-hade/dino-arla-pare-hade-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/16-pare-hade/dino-arla-pare-hade-04-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/16-pare-hade/dino-arla-pare-hade-04-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/16-pare-hade/dino-arla-pare-hade-04-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/16-pare-hade/dino-arla-pare-hade-04.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Ensuring Reliability and Transparency </div> <h2 id="impact-on-the-local-and-national-economy">Impact on the Local and National Economy</h2> <p>The swift activation of the power supply for PT Pare Hade 3 marks a significant milestone not only for the company but also for the local community. With the milling machines now operational, there is an anticipated increase in rice processing capacity, boosting both local employment and national rice output.</p> <p>This collaboration between PLN and local enterprises underscores a shared commitment to innovation and excellence in the agricultural sector. As Cikedung continues to contribute to the national rice reserves, the community stands as a testament to what can be achieved when industry and utilities unite for the greater good.</p> <p>In conclusion, the same-day service activation by PLN Cikedung for PT Pare Hade 3 is more than just a convenience—it’s a catalyst for economic growth and a beacon of progress for the rice milling industry in Cikedung. Through reliable power supply and expert oversight, the collaboration ensures that Cikedung remains at the forefront of national rice production.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="pln"/><category term="pln"/><category term="cikedung"/><category term="indramayu"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nestled in the productive precincts of Indramayu, Cikedung stands proudly as a national rice granary, a title it has earned through years of dedicated cultivation and production. As technology continues to enhance agricultural processes, the importance of reliable electricity to power essential machinery cannot be overstated. This is where PLN Cikedung steps in, ensuring that the wheels of rice milling operations spin without interruption.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PLN Scholar Project - A Continued Collaboration with PLN’s Division of Corporate Business and Investment, Part 2</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/09/21/pln-scholar-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PLN Scholar Project - A Continued Collaboration with PLN’s Division of Corporate Business and Investment, Part 2"/><published>2023-09-21T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-21T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/09/21/pln-scholar-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/09/21/pln-scholar-2.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2> <p>The PLN Scholar Project has been making waves in the academic and energy sectors. In this second installment of our blog series on the PLN Scholar Project, we delve deeper into the ongoing collaboration with PLN’s Division of Corporate Business and Investment. Notably, Dino, a key figure in this endeavor, has been invited back to PLN’s headquarters in South Jakarta to further the initiative.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/15-pln-scholar-2/dino-arla-pln-scholar-2-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/15-pln-scholar-2/dino-arla-pln-scholar-2-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/15-pln-scholar-2/dino-arla-pln-scholar-2-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/15-pln-scholar-2/dino-arla-pln-scholar-2-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/15-pln-scholar-2/dino-arla-pln-scholar-2-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/15-pln-scholar-2/dino-arla-pln-scholar-2-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/15-pln-scholar-2/dino-arla-pln-scholar-2-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/15-pln-scholar-2/dino-arla-pln-scholar-2-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> PLN Scholar Project Part 2 </div> <h2 id="background">Background</h2> <p>The PLN Scholar Project is an innovative initiative aimed at fostering collaboration between academic scholars and PLN’s various divisions, leveraging research to enhance operational efficiency and strategic investment. The project is uniquely positioned to bridge the gap between academia and industry, creating a synergy that propels both spheres forward.</p> <h2 id="dinos-role-in-the-collaboration">Dino’s Role in the Collaboration</h2> <p>Dino, an esteemed full stack web developer, has played a pivotal role in the PLN Scholar Project. His initial involvement laid the groundwork for the second phase of the collaboration. Dino’s expertise in web development and his ability to create and manage complex digital platforms have been instrumental in supporting PLN’s technological infrastructure.</p> <p>His recent invitation back to the PLN headquarters in South Jakarta signifies a renewed commitment to the project. Dino’s return to the capital marks the beginning of a new chapter in the partnership, with promising opportunities for innovation and growth in PLN’s digital landscape.</p> <h2 id="key-objectives-of-the-second-phase">Key Objectives of the Second Phase</h2> <p>The continuation of the PLN Scholar Project aims to achieve several objectives:</p> <ol> <li>Enhanced Digital Collaborations: Building on existing digital platforms, the second phase seeks to expand and deepen the digital collaborations, focusing on emerging technology challenges and opportunities.</li> <li>Strategic Technological Insights: By leveraging Dino’s web development expertise, the project aims to provide PLN’s Division of Corporate Business and Investment with robust insights into strategic digital investments and advancements.</li> <li>Operational Efficiency through Technology: Identifying innovative solutions to improve PLN’s operational efficiency, using cutting-edge web technologies and development methodologies.</li> <li>Digital Transformation: Promoting digital transformation practices that align with global technological trends and PLN’s commitment to modernization.</li> </ol> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/15-pln-scholar-2/dino-arla-pln-scholar-2-04-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/15-pln-scholar-2/dino-arla-pln-scholar-2-04-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/15-pln-scholar-2/dino-arla-pln-scholar-2-04-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/15-pln-scholar-2/dino-arla-pln-scholar-2-04.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/15-pln-scholar-2/dino-arla-pln-scholar-2-05-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/15-pln-scholar-2/dino-arla-pln-scholar-2-05-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/15-pln-scholar-2/dino-arla-pln-scholar-2-05-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/15-pln-scholar-2/dino-arla-pln-scholar-2-05.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> PLN Scholar Project Part 2 </div> <h2 id="looking-forward">Looking Forward</h2> <p>The PLN Scholar Project, particularly in its second installment, continues to be a beacon of innovation, collaboration, and mutual growth. Dino’s return to Jakarta Southern Headquarters is a testament to the success and the potential of this ongoing partnership. As the project unfolds, it promises to deliver tangible benefits not only to PLN but also to the academic community and the broader energy sector.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/15-pln-scholar-2/dino-arla-pln-scholar-2-03-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/15-pln-scholar-2/dino-arla-pln-scholar-2-03-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/15-pln-scholar-2/dino-arla-pln-scholar-2-03-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/15-pln-scholar-2/dino-arla-pln-scholar-2-03.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> At-Taqwa Mosque of PLN HQ </div> <p>Stay tuned for more updates on this exciting collaboration and see how the PLN Scholar Project continues to shape the future of energy in Indonesia through technological innovation.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="pln"/><category term="pln"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this second installment of our blog series on the PLN Scholar Project, we delve deeper into the ongoing collaboration with PLN's Division of Corporate Business and Investment. Notably, Dino, a key figure in this endeavor, has been invited back to PLN's headquarters in South Jakarta to further the initiative.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating Indonesia’s 78th Independence Day - Advancing Together Towards a Progressive Nation, from PLN Cikedung for a Prosperous Indonesia</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/08/17/independence-day.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating Indonesia’s 78th Independence Day - Advancing Together Towards a Progressive Nation, from PLN Cikedung for a Prosperous Indonesia"/><published>2023-08-17T13:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-17T13:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/08/17/independence-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/08/17/independence-day.html"><![CDATA[<p>As the red and white flags flutter proudly across our archipelago, we come together to celebrate the 78th Independence Day of the Republic of Indonesia. This year, our theme is “Terus Melaju Untuk Indonesia Maju,” which translates to “Advancing Together Towards a Progressive Nation.” This theme not only reflects our collective aspiration to drive Indonesia forward but also echoes the relentless efforts of all Indonesians in contributing to the nation’s progress.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/13-independence-day/dino-arla-independence-day-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/13-independence-day/dino-arla-independence-day-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/13-independence-day/dino-arla-independence-day-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/13-independence-day/dino-arla-independence-day-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Celebrating Indonesia’s 78th Independence Day - Advancing Together Towards a Progressive Nation </div> <h2 id="a-time-for-reflection-and-celebration">A Time for Reflection and Celebration</h2> <p>Independence Day is a time for both reflection and celebration. It’s an opportunity for us to remember the sacrifices made by our forefathers, who fought valiantly to secure the freedom we enjoy today. It is also a moment to celebrate the rich cultural heritage and unity in diversity that is Indonesia. As we reflect on our journey, we recognize the strides we have made in various sectors and the challenges that lie ahead.</p> <h2 id="pln-cikedung-powering-indonesias-progress">PLN Cikedung: Powering Indonesia’s Progress</h2> <p>At PLN Cikedung, we are proud to play a vital role in the nation’s development. As part of the state electricity company, we are committed to ensuring every corner of our nation is illuminated with reliable and sustainable energy. Our dedication to powering homes, industries, and communities is unwavering, and we continue to innovate and improve our services to meet the growing demands of a modernizing Indonesia.</p> <h2 id="harnessing-energy-for-sustainable-growth">Harnessing Energy for Sustainable Growth</h2> <p>In line with this year’s theme, “Advancing Together Towards a Progressive Nation,” PLN Cikedung is focusing on sustainable growth. We are investing in renewable energy sources and advancing technology to ensure a greener and more sustainable future. By harnessing the power of nature, from solar to wind, we aim to reduce our carbon footprint and contribute to global efforts against climate change.</p> <h2 id="united-for-a-better-tomorrow">United for a Better Tomorrow</h2> <p>As we celebrate this Independence Day, let us remember that every small effort counts. Whether it’s by conserving energy or supporting local communities, each one of us can contribute to national progress. Together, we can build an Indonesia that is not just self-sufficient but also respected on the global stage.</p> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>On this auspicious day, we at PLN Cikedung extend our warmest wishes to all Indonesians. “Dirgahayu Republik Indonesia, Selamat Hari Kemerdekaan ke-78.” May we continue to march forward, hand in hand, towards a brighter, more prosperous future. Together, we advance for Indonesia’s success.</p> <p>Let us strive to make this Independence Day not just a celebration of our past achievements but a commitment to our future endeavors. Happy Independence Day, Indonesia!</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="pln"/><category term="pln"/><category term="cikedung"/><category term="indramayu"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the red and white flags flutter proudly across our archipelago, we come together to celebrate the 78th Independence Day of the Republic of Indonesia. This year, our theme is Terus Melaju Untuk Indonesia Maju, which translates to Advancing Together Towards a Progressive Nation.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Utilizing Solar Power Systems on the Roof of GAIA Kubu Raya Mall’s Parking Area in West Kalimantan</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/energy/2023/08/13/solar-power.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Utilizing Solar Power Systems on the Roof of GAIA Kubu Raya Mall’s Parking Area in West Kalimantan"/><published>2023-08-13T19:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-13T19:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/energy/2023/08/13/solar-power</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/energy/2023/08/13/solar-power.html"><![CDATA[<p>In recent years, the push towards sustainable and renewable energy sources has been increasingly evident across the globe. More organizations are recognizing the importance of reducing their carbon footprints and are implementing green technology in their infrastructure. One such example can be seen in the innovative initiative of the GAIA Kubu Raya Mall in West Kalimantan, Indonesia, where they have installed Solar Power Systems on the roof of their parking area.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Utilizing Solar Power Systems on the Roof of GAIA Kubu Raya Mall's Parking Area in West Kalimantan </div> <h2 id="the-initiative">The Initiative</h2> <p>The GAIA Kubu Raya Mall has set a benchmark by integrating solar power technology into their parking facilities. This initiative demonstrates a commitment to sustainable development and environmental stewardship by utilizing the vast potential of solar energy. By harnessing solar power, the mall not only reduces its dependence on non-renewable energy sources but also significantly cuts down on its electricity costs.</p> <h2 id="how-it-works">How It Works</h2> <p>The solar power system, commonly referred to as Photovoltaic (PV) panels, captures sunlight and converts it into electricity. These panels are mounted on the roof of the parking area, taking full advantage of the large, open space which is often bathed in sunlight throughout the day. The electricity generated is then used to power various sections of the mall, from lighting to other electrical appliances, thereby promoting energy efficiency.</p> <h2 id="benefits">Benefits</h2> <ol> <li>Cost Reduction: By generating its own electricity, the mall significantly reduces its energy expenses.</li> <li>Environmental Impact: Reducing reliance on fossil fuels means fewer greenhouse gas emissions, contributing to a cleaner environment.</li> <li>Energy Independence: Harnessing solar energy provides the mall with a certain degree of energy independence, lessening its vulnerability to external power shortages or price hikes.</li> <li>Increased Property Value: Installing solar panels can increase the overall property value due to the growing appeal of sustainable technologies.</li> </ol> <h2 id="challenges-and-solutions">Challenges and Solutions</h2> <p>While the implementation of solar panels poses some challenges, such as the initial investment cost and maintenance requirements, these are often offset by government incentives and the long-term savings incurred. The increase in solar technology efficiency and decrease in costs over recent years have also made such projects more accessible and viable.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-03-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-03-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-03-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-03.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Utilizing Solar Power Systems on the Roof of GAIA Kubu Raya Mall's Parking Area in West Kalimantan </div> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>The installation of solar power systems on the parking roof of the GAIA Kubu Raya Mall is an exemplary step towards sustainable development. This initiative not only illustrates the potential of renewable energy in public infrastructure but also sets a precedent for other businesses in the region to follow. As more corporations adopt similar technologies, the cumulative effect could lead to significant environmental benefits and progression towards a greener future.</p> <p>As the world continues to grapple with climate change and energy challenges, innovative solutions such as the use of solar power in commercial spaces are crucial in driving the change towards a sustainable future. The GAIA Kubu Raya Mall stands as a testament to the power of renewable energy in transforming our world.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="energy"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[One such example can be seen in the innovative initiative of the GAIA Kubu Raya Mall in West Kalimantan, Indonesia, where they have installed Solar Power Systems on the roof of their parking area.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Maintaining Harmony and Sanity with Colleagues through Shared Meals</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/08/07/shared-meals.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Maintaining Harmony and Sanity with Colleagues through Shared Meals"/><published>2023-08-07T15:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-07T15:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/08/07/shared-meals</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/08/07/shared-meals.html"><![CDATA[<p>In today’s fast-paced work environment, maintaining harmony and sanity among colleagues can often be a challenging task. Between deadlines, meetings, and the constant buzz of emails, it’s easy to lose sight of the human aspect in the workplace. One simple yet effective way to foster a supportive and collaborative environment is by sharing meals together. Breaking bread with colleagues not only nourishes the body but also builds a sense of community and understanding, which are essential for a harmonious workplace.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/11-shared-meals/dino-arla-meals-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/11-shared-meals/dino-arla-meals-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/11-shared-meals/dino-arla-meals-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/11-shared-meals/dino-arla-meals-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/11-shared-meals/dino-arla-meals-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/11-shared-meals/dino-arla-meals-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/11-shared-meals/dino-arla-meals-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/11-shared-meals/dino-arla-meals-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Maintaining Harmony and Sanity with Colleagues through Shared Meals </div> <h2 id="the-power-of-shared-meals">The Power of Shared Meals</h2> <p>Sharing a meal with colleagues can break down barriers and create a more relaxed and open atmosphere. Eating together allows for informal interactions that help build personal connections beyond work-related discussions. These moments pave the way for better communication, increased trust, and more effective teamwork, ultimately leading to improved productivity and a happier workplace.</p> <p>Moreover, meals provide a platform for employees to express themselves, share ideas, and discuss topics not covered in formal meetings. It’s an opportunity to gain insights into each other’s personality, background, and life outside of work. This understanding is crucial in fostering empathy and cooperation among team members.</p> <h2 id="enhancing-mental-well-being">Enhancing Mental Well-being</h2> <p>Stress and pressure are inevitable in any job, but having supportive colleagues can make a significant difference. Shared meals provide a break from the routine, allowing everyone to de-stress and recharge in a casual setting. This can significantly enhance mental well-being and reduce burnout.</p> <p>Furthermore, the social interaction that comes with eating together can help alleviate feelings of isolation and loneliness, which are common in many work environments, especially with the rise of remote working. Regularly scheduled team lunches or dinners can ensure that all members feel included and valued.</p> <h2 id="tips-for-organizing-shared-meals">Tips for Organizing Shared Meals</h2> <ol> <li>Schedule Regular Meals: Set a regular schedule for team lunches or breakfasts, ensuring it becomes a part of the team culture. This could be a weekly or monthly event that everyone looks forward to.</li> <li>Inclusive Environment: Make sure that the meals cater to all dietary restrictions and preferences to ensure everyone feels comfortable and included.</li> <li>Mix It Up: Encourage team members to suggest different cuisines or themes to keep things exciting. This not only introduces variety but also allows employees to share a part of their culture with others.</li> </ol> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>Maintaining harmony and sanity in the workplace doesn’t necessarily require complex strategies or significant investments. Sometimes, simple acts like sharing a meal can bridge gaps, foster understanding, and build a strong, cohesive team. As we move forward in an ever-evolving work landscape, let’s not forget the power of coming together over good food and conversation to nurture both body and spirit.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="pln"/><category term="work"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[One simple yet effective way to foster a supportive and collaborative environment is by sharing meals together. Breaking bread with colleagues not only nourishes the body but also builds a sense of community and understanding, which are essential for a harmonious workplace.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A New Chapter - Dino Begins His Academic Journey as a Graduate Student at Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember, VIVAT!</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/academic/2023/07/30/mmt-start.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A New Chapter - Dino Begins His Academic Journey as a Graduate Student at Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember, VIVAT!"/><published>2023-07-30T13:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-30T13:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/academic/2023/07/30/mmt-start</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/academic/2023/07/30/mmt-start.html"><![CDATA[<p>In the ever-evolving world of technology and business, innovation and advanced knowledge have become crucial drivers of success. It is in this dynamic landscape that Dino has embarked on a thrilling new chapter in his life, beginning his journey as a graduate student at the prestigious Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember (ITS). Pursuing a Master’s Degree in Technology Management with a focus on Business Analytics, Dino is poised to gain invaluable insights and skills that will pave the way for a promising career.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/10-mmt/dino-arla-mmt-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/10-mmt/dino-arla-mmt-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/10-mmt/dino-arla-mmt-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/10-mmt/dino-arla-mmt-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/10-mmt/dino-arla-mmt-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/10-mmt/dino-arla-mmt-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/10-mmt/dino-arla-mmt-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/10-mmt/dino-arla-mmt-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Officially becomes a graduate student of MMT ITS </div> <h2 id="the-decision-to-advance-academically">The Decision to Advance Academically</h2> <p>Dino’s decision to further his education was fueled by his passion for technology and his desire to harness its power for strategic business solutions. As industries increasingly rely on data-driven decision-making, Dino recognized the importance of equipping himself with the latest analytical tools and methodologies. The Master’s program in Technology Management at ITS, renowned for its cutting-edge curriculum and expert faculty, presented the perfect opportunity to achieve this.</p> <h2 id="why-business-analytics">Why Business Analytics?</h2> <p>Business Analytics is at the heart of modern strategic business management, bridging the gap between technology and decision-making. By focusing on this specialization, Dino aims to master the art of transforming complex data into actionable insights. This skill is essential for organizations striving to optimize their operations and achieve competitive advantages in today’s data-saturated world.</p> <h2 id="life-as-a-graduate-student-at-its">Life as a Graduate Student at ITS</h2> <p>Embarking on this academic journey at ITS, Dino looks forward to an enriching experience filled with learning, growth, and collaboration. The university’s vibrant academic environment, coupled with state-of-the-art facilities and resources, provides a conducive setting for advanced learning. Dino is eager to engage with a diverse community of fellow students and professionals, exchanging ideas and perspectives that will enhance his understanding and capabilities.</p> <h2 id="looking-ahead">Looking Ahead</h2> <p>As Dino delves into his studies, he is excited about the numerous opportunities that lie ahead. The program promises a blend of theoretical knowledge and practical application, ensuring that graduates emerge as well-rounded, competent professionals. With a keen focus on real-world challenges and solutions, Dino is confident that his time at ITS will equip him with the expertise needed to make a meaningful impact in the field of technology management.</p> <p>In conclusion, Dino’s journey as a graduate student at Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember marks a significant milestone in his career. The skills and knowledge he acquires will not only prepare him for future challenges but will also empower him to be a leader in the world of technological innovation and business analytics.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="academic"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the ever-evolving world of technology and business, innovation and advanced knowledge have become crucial drivers of success. It is in this dynamic landscape that Dino has embarked on a thrilling new chapter in his life, beginning his journey as a graduate student at the prestigious Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember (ITS)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Staying Motivated at Work by Always Having Breakfast</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/family/2023/07/27/breakfast.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Staying Motivated at Work by Always Having Breakfast"/><published>2023-07-27T11:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-27T11:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/family/2023/07/27/breakfast</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/family/2023/07/27/breakfast.html"><![CDATA[<p>In our fast-paced world, work often takes precedence over everything else in our lives. With deadlines looming and endless tasks on our to-do lists, maintaining a high level of energy and motivation can be a real challenge. However, there’s one simple habit that can make a significant difference: starting your day with a nutritious breakfast. Here’s why having breakfast is essential for staying motivated at work.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/09-breakfast/dino-arla-breakfast-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/09-breakfast/dino-arla-breakfast-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/09-breakfast/dino-arla-breakfast-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/09-breakfast/dino-arla-breakfast-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/09-breakfast/dino-arla-breakfast-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/09-breakfast/dino-arla-breakfast-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/09-breakfast/dino-arla-breakfast-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/09-breakfast/dino-arla-breakfast-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Staying Motivated at Work by Always Having Breakfast </div> <h2 id="the-significance-of-breakfast">The Significance of Breakfast</h2> <p>Breakfast is often referred to as the most important meal of the day. After a long night of fasting, our bodies need fuel to kickstart the day. Eating a well-balanced breakfast provides the necessary nutrients and energy to keep us productive and focused.</p> <p>Studies have shown that individuals who eat breakfast tend to have better concentration, memory, and cognitive functions. This can lead to increased productivity and efficiency at work, allowing you to tackle tasks more effectively.</p> <h2 id="boosting-energy-and-mood">Boosting Energy and Mood</h2> <p>Skipping breakfast can leave you feeling sluggish and irritable, making it harder to stay motivated. On the other hand, having breakfast helps stabilize your blood sugar levels, which can prevent energy crashes later in the day.</p> <p>Including complex carbohydrates, protein, and healthy fats in your breakfast can provide sustained energy and improve your mood, making it easier to face the challenges of the workday with a positive attitude.</p> <h2 id="managing-a-long-commute">Managing a Long Commute</h2> <p>For many, like Dino who spends about an hour commuting from home to the office, having breakfast becomes even more crucial. The long distance can add stress and fatigue, but starting the day with a nutritious meal helps maintain energy levels during the commute and upon arrival at work.</p> <h2 id="encouraging-healthier-choices">Encouraging Healthier Choices</h2> <p>Starting the day with breakfast can set a precedence for making healthier food choices throughout the day. When you begin your day with healthy eating habits, you’re more likely to continue those habits, choosing nutritious snacks and meals that support your overall well-being.</p> <p>Additionally, having breakfast can prevent overeating later in the day, which often happens when people skip this vital meal. By maintaining a balanced diet, you’ll find it easier to keep your energy levels up and remain motivated at work.</p> <h2 id="tips-for-a-healthy-breakfast">Tips for a Healthy Breakfast</h2> <ol> <li>Plan Ahead: Prepare your breakfast the night before to save time in the morning.</li> <li>Balance Your Plate: Include whole grains, lean proteins, and fruits or vegetables in your breakfast.</li> <li>Stay Hydrated: Don’t forget to drink water or have a glass of fresh juice to start your day.</li> <li>Mindful Eating: Take time to enjoy your breakfast without distractions. Being mindful of what you eat can improve digestion and satisfaction.</li> </ol> <p>In conclusion, maintaining motivation at work starts with fueling your body appropriately each morning. By making breakfast a non-negotiable part of your routine, you’re setting yourself up for a day of productivity, energy, and positivity. So, keep that breakfast bowl ready and embrace the day with renewed vigor and enthusiasm!</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="family"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[With deadlines looming and endless tasks on our to-do lists, maintaining a high level of energy and motivation can be a real challenge. However, there’s one simple habit that can make a significant difference, starting your day with a nutritious breakfast. Here’s why having breakfast is essential for staying motivated at work.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Companions of PLN in Power Generation - Now Become a Proud Husbands and Fatherman</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/friendship/2023/07/22/companion-pln.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Companions of PLN in Power Generation - Now Become a Proud Husbands and Fatherman"/><published>2023-07-22T23:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-22T23:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/friendship/2023/07/22/companion-pln</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/friendship/2023/07/22/companion-pln.html"><![CDATA[<p>In the ever-evolving world of power generation, a group of young, spirited individuals embarked on a journey that would not only shape their careers but also their personal lives. These companions from PLN (Perusahaan Listrik Negara), Indonesia’s state electricity company, have grown together professionally and personally, transitioning from being fresh graduates to seasoned professionals, and now, loving husbands and proud fathers.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> The Companions of PLN in Power Generation </div> <h2 id="the-beginnings">The Beginnings</h2> <p>The story of these comrades began in the bustling halls of PLN, where they met as new recruits eager to make a mark in the field of power generation. Their shared mission to ensure reliable electricity supply to millions of Indonesians forged a bond that transcended professional boundaries. Late-night shifts, challenging projects, and countless brainstorming sessions were the backdrop to their budding camaraderie.</p> <h2 id="the-journey-in-power-generation">The Journey in Power Generation</h2> <p>Working in power generation is no small feat. It demands technical expertise, resilience, and a commitment to continuous learning. These companions quickly adapted to the dynamic environment, supporting each other through the complexities of the job. They celebrated successes and consoled one another in the face of setbacks, learning invaluable lessons along the way.</p> <h2 id="from-colleagues-to-friends">From Colleagues to Friends</h2> <p>As time passed, their relationships deepened. What started as professional collaboration blossomed into genuine friendships. They shared not only career aspirations but also personal dreams and challenges. Weekend get-togethers became a norm, and soon, they were an integral part of each other’s lives outside of work.</p> <h2 id="the-next-chapter-marriage-and-parenthood">The Next Chapter: Marriage and Parenthood</h2> <p>Life took a beautiful turn when these companions found love and embarked on the journey of marriage. Their weddings were joyous occasions, attended by their PLN colleagues who had become more like family. As they transitioned into married life, they continued to support each other, now sharing advice on balancing work and personal responsibilities.</p> <p>The arrival of children marked another milestone in their lives. Parenthood brought its own set of challenges and joys, and these friends found new ways to connect, swapping stories about sleepless nights and first steps. They cherished the opportunity to watch their children grow, hopeful for a future where they could share the tales of their enduring friendship and professional journey.</p> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>Today, these companions of PLN, who once embarked on a journey in power generation, stand as exemplars of balance and perseverance. They have shown that it is possible to nurture both a successful career and a fulfilling family life. Their story is a testament to the power of friendship, unity, and shared experiences, reminding us that while the path to success is important, it is the companions we travel with that truly enrich our lives.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="friendship"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[These companions from PLN (Perusahaan Listrik Negara), Indonesia's state electricity company, have grown together professionally and personally, transitioning from being fresh graduates to seasoned professionals, and now, loving husbands and proud fathers.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Togetherness with the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/06/15/cikedung-p2tl.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Togetherness with the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team"/><published>2023-06-15T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-15T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/06/15/cikedung-p2tl</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/06/15/cikedung-p2tl.html"><![CDATA[<p>In the quaint district of Cikedung, a remarkable team of dedicated individuals is making a significant difference in the community. Led by the dynamic Dino Arla, who serves as the Commander of Energy Transactions, the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team works tirelessly to ensure that electricity usage in the area is both efficient and fair. But beyond their professional commitments, there exists a strong sense of camaraderie and togetherness among the team members that sets them apart.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-08-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-08-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-08-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-08.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-04-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-04-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-04-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-04.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team </div> <h2 id="fostering-a-family-like-atmosphere">Fostering a Family-Like Atmosphere</h2> <p>Under Dino Arla’s leadership, every individual in the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team is valued not only for their skills and contributions but also for their unique personalities. Dino has instilled a culture that fosters an environment more like a family than a workplace. Regular team-building activities, such as community outings and participation in local events, help strengthen the bonds between members. Through these activities, team members learn to trust and rely on each other, which is crucial in their line of work.</p> <h2 id="bringing-the-community-together">Bringing the Community Together</h2> <p>The PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team, guided by Dino’s strategic vision, is deeply integrated into the community. They actively engage with locals to educate them about electricity usage and safety. These interactions are not just formalities but are opportunities for the team to connect with residents on a personal level. This approach, championed by Dino, has created a strong rapport between the team and the community, making their enforcement efforts more effective and welcomed.</p> <h2 id="overcoming-challenges-together">Overcoming Challenges Together</h2> <p>The job of ensuring proper electricity usage is not without its challenges. Under Dino Arla’s capable supervision, the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team often faces difficult situations, such as dealing with illegal electricity connections or addressing power shortages. However, the sense of unity among the team members allows them to face these challenges head-on. They support each other through thick and thin, celebrating successes and learning from setbacks together.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-03-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-03-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-03-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-03.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team - Meeting and Evaluation </div> <h2 id="significant-financial-impact">Significant Financial Impact</h2> <p>The dedication and efficiency of the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team have significantly contributed to the recovery and saving of company income, exceeding 4 billion rupiahs. This remarkable achievement underscores the team’s effectiveness in combating electricity misuse and optimizing energy distribution.</p> <h2 id="the-impact-of-togetherness">The Impact of Togetherness</h2> <p>The togetherness of the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team, led by Dino Arla, has had a profound impact on both their work and their lives. It has improved their effectiveness in ensuring proper electricity usage and has contributed to a positive work environment that prioritizes well-being and collaboration. This unity, cultivated by Dino, is reflected in their interactions with the community and is a key factor in the team’s success.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-05-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-05-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-05-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-05.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-06-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-06-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-06-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-06.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-07-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-07-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-07-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-07.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team </div> <p>In conclusion, with Dino Arla at the helm, the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team stands as a model of how teamwork and togetherness can lead to success and satisfaction in professional endeavors. Their dedication to their work and each other is a testament to the power of unity and community spirit.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="pln"/><category term="cikedung"/><category term="indramayu"/><category term="acceleraterenewableenergy"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Led by the dynamic Dino Arla, who serves as the Commander of Energy Transactions, the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team works tirelessly to ensure that electricity usage in the area is both efficient and fair.]]></summary></entry></feed>