<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://dinoarla.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://dinoarla.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-02-02T12:26:41+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Notes of a dedication | Dino Arla</title><subtitle>Dino Arla is an Electrical Engineer at PLN. Graduate student of MMT ITS. Corporate Innovator Winner. Machine Learning &amp; AI Enthusiast. Full Stack Web Developer. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Utilizing Solar Power Systems on the Roof of GAIA Kubu Raya Mall’s Parking Area in West Kalimantan</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/energy/2023/08/13/solar-power.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Utilizing Solar Power Systems on the Roof of GAIA Kubu Raya Mall’s Parking Area in West Kalimantan"/><published>2023-08-13T19:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-13T19:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/energy/2023/08/13/solar-power</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/energy/2023/08/13/solar-power.html"><![CDATA[<p>In recent years, the push towards sustainable and renewable energy sources has been increasingly evident across the globe. More organizations are recognizing the importance of reducing their carbon footprints and are implementing green technology in their infrastructure. One such example can be seen in the innovative initiative of the GAIA Kubu Raya Mall in West Kalimantan, Indonesia, where they have installed Solar Power Systems on the roof of their parking area.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Utilizing Solar Power Systems on the Roof of GAIA Kubu Raya Mall's Parking Area in West Kalimantan </div> <h2 id="the-initiative">The Initiative</h2> <p>The GAIA Kubu Raya Mall has set a benchmark by integrating solar power technology into their parking facilities. This initiative demonstrates a commitment to sustainable development and environmental stewardship by utilizing the vast potential of solar energy. By harnessing solar power, the mall not only reduces its dependence on non-renewable energy sources but also significantly cuts down on its electricity costs.</p> <h2 id="how-it-works">How It Works</h2> <p>The solar power system, commonly referred to as Photovoltaic (PV) panels, captures sunlight and converts it into electricity. These panels are mounted on the roof of the parking area, taking full advantage of the large, open space which is often bathed in sunlight throughout the day. The electricity generated is then used to power various sections of the mall, from lighting to other electrical appliances, thereby promoting energy efficiency.</p> <h2 id="benefits">Benefits</h2> <ol> <li>Cost Reduction: By generating its own electricity, the mall significantly reduces its energy expenses.</li> <li>Environmental Impact: Reducing reliance on fossil fuels means fewer greenhouse gas emissions, contributing to a cleaner environment.</li> <li>Energy Independence: Harnessing solar energy provides the mall with a certain degree of energy independence, lessening its vulnerability to external power shortages or price hikes.</li> <li>Increased Property Value: Installing solar panels can increase the overall property value due to the growing appeal of sustainable technologies.</li> </ol> <h2 id="challenges-and-solutions">Challenges and Solutions</h2> <p>While the implementation of solar panels poses some challenges, such as the initial investment cost and maintenance requirements, these are often offset by government incentives and the long-term savings incurred. The increase in solar technology efficiency and decrease in costs over recent years have also made such projects more accessible and viable.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-03-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-03-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-03-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/12-solar-power/dino-arla-solar-03.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Utilizing Solar Power Systems on the Roof of GAIA Kubu Raya Mall's Parking Area in West Kalimantan </div> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>The installation of solar power systems on the parking roof of the GAIA Kubu Raya Mall is an exemplary step towards sustainable development. This initiative not only illustrates the potential of renewable energy in public infrastructure but also sets a precedent for other businesses in the region to follow. As more corporations adopt similar technologies, the cumulative effect could lead to significant environmental benefits and progression towards a greener future.</p> <p>As the world continues to grapple with climate change and energy challenges, innovative solutions such as the use of solar power in commercial spaces are crucial in driving the change towards a sustainable future. The GAIA Kubu Raya Mall stands as a testament to the power of renewable energy in transforming our world.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="energy"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[One such example can be seen in the innovative initiative of the GAIA Kubu Raya Mall in West Kalimantan, Indonesia, where they have installed Solar Power Systems on the roof of their parking area.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Maintaining Harmony and Sanity with Colleagues through Shared Meals</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/08/07/shared-meals.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Maintaining Harmony and Sanity with Colleagues through Shared Meals"/><published>2023-08-07T15:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-07T15:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/08/07/shared-meals</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/08/07/shared-meals.html"><![CDATA[<p>In today’s fast-paced work environment, maintaining harmony and sanity among colleagues can often be a challenging task. Between deadlines, meetings, and the constant buzz of emails, it’s easy to lose sight of the human aspect in the workplace. One simple yet effective way to foster a supportive and collaborative environment is by sharing meals together. Breaking bread with colleagues not only nourishes the body but also builds a sense of community and understanding, which are essential for a harmonious workplace.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/11-shared-meals/dino-arla-meals-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/11-shared-meals/dino-arla-meals-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/11-shared-meals/dino-arla-meals-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/11-shared-meals/dino-arla-meals-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/11-shared-meals/dino-arla-meals-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/11-shared-meals/dino-arla-meals-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/11-shared-meals/dino-arla-meals-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/11-shared-meals/dino-arla-meals-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Maintaining Harmony and Sanity with Colleagues through Shared Meals </div> <h2 id="the-power-of-shared-meals">The Power of Shared Meals</h2> <p>Sharing a meal with colleagues can break down barriers and create a more relaxed and open atmosphere. Eating together allows for informal interactions that help build personal connections beyond work-related discussions. These moments pave the way for better communication, increased trust, and more effective teamwork, ultimately leading to improved productivity and a happier workplace.</p> <p>Moreover, meals provide a platform for employees to express themselves, share ideas, and discuss topics not covered in formal meetings. It’s an opportunity to gain insights into each other’s personality, background, and life outside of work. This understanding is crucial in fostering empathy and cooperation among team members.</p> <h2 id="enhancing-mental-well-being">Enhancing Mental Well-being</h2> <p>Stress and pressure are inevitable in any job, but having supportive colleagues can make a significant difference. Shared meals provide a break from the routine, allowing everyone to de-stress and recharge in a casual setting. This can significantly enhance mental well-being and reduce burnout.</p> <p>Furthermore, the social interaction that comes with eating together can help alleviate feelings of isolation and loneliness, which are common in many work environments, especially with the rise of remote working. Regularly scheduled team lunches or dinners can ensure that all members feel included and valued.</p> <h2 id="tips-for-organizing-shared-meals">Tips for Organizing Shared Meals</h2> <ol> <li>Schedule Regular Meals: Set a regular schedule for team lunches or breakfasts, ensuring it becomes a part of the team culture. This could be a weekly or monthly event that everyone looks forward to.</li> <li>Inclusive Environment: Make sure that the meals cater to all dietary restrictions and preferences to ensure everyone feels comfortable and included.</li> <li>Mix It Up: Encourage team members to suggest different cuisines or themes to keep things exciting. This not only introduces variety but also allows employees to share a part of their culture with others.</li> </ol> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>Maintaining harmony and sanity in the workplace doesn’t necessarily require complex strategies or significant investments. Sometimes, simple acts like sharing a meal can bridge gaps, foster understanding, and build a strong, cohesive team. As we move forward in an ever-evolving work landscape, let’s not forget the power of coming together over good food and conversation to nurture both body and spirit.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="pln"/><category term="work"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[One simple yet effective way to foster a supportive and collaborative environment is by sharing meals together. Breaking bread with colleagues not only nourishes the body but also builds a sense of community and understanding, which are essential for a harmonious workplace.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A New Chapter - Dino Begins His Academic Journey as a Graduate Student at Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember, VIVAT!</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/academic/2023/07/30/mmt-start.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A New Chapter - Dino Begins His Academic Journey as a Graduate Student at Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember, VIVAT!"/><published>2023-07-30T13:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-30T13:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/academic/2023/07/30/mmt-start</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/academic/2023/07/30/mmt-start.html"><![CDATA[<p>In the ever-evolving world of technology and business, innovation and advanced knowledge have become crucial drivers of success. It is in this dynamic landscape that Dino has embarked on a thrilling new chapter in his life, beginning his journey as a graduate student at the prestigious Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember (ITS). Pursuing a Master’s Degree in Technology Management with a focus on Business Analytics, Dino is poised to gain invaluable insights and skills that will pave the way for a promising career.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/10-mmt/dino-arla-mmt-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/10-mmt/dino-arla-mmt-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/10-mmt/dino-arla-mmt-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/10-mmt/dino-arla-mmt-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/10-mmt/dino-arla-mmt-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/10-mmt/dino-arla-mmt-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/10-mmt/dino-arla-mmt-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/10-mmt/dino-arla-mmt-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Officially becomes a graduate student of MMT ITS </div> <h2 id="the-decision-to-advance-academically">The Decision to Advance Academically</h2> <p>Dino’s decision to further his education was fueled by his passion for technology and his desire to harness its power for strategic business solutions. As industries increasingly rely on data-driven decision-making, Dino recognized the importance of equipping himself with the latest analytical tools and methodologies. The Master’s program in Technology Management at ITS, renowned for its cutting-edge curriculum and expert faculty, presented the perfect opportunity to achieve this.</p> <h2 id="why-business-analytics">Why Business Analytics?</h2> <p>Business Analytics is at the heart of modern strategic business management, bridging the gap between technology and decision-making. By focusing on this specialization, Dino aims to master the art of transforming complex data into actionable insights. This skill is essential for organizations striving to optimize their operations and achieve competitive advantages in today’s data-saturated world.</p> <h2 id="life-as-a-graduate-student-at-its">Life as a Graduate Student at ITS</h2> <p>Embarking on this academic journey at ITS, Dino looks forward to an enriching experience filled with learning, growth, and collaboration. The university’s vibrant academic environment, coupled with state-of-the-art facilities and resources, provides a conducive setting for advanced learning. Dino is eager to engage with a diverse community of fellow students and professionals, exchanging ideas and perspectives that will enhance his understanding and capabilities.</p> <h2 id="looking-ahead">Looking Ahead</h2> <p>As Dino delves into his studies, he is excited about the numerous opportunities that lie ahead. The program promises a blend of theoretical knowledge and practical application, ensuring that graduates emerge as well-rounded, competent professionals. With a keen focus on real-world challenges and solutions, Dino is confident that his time at ITS will equip him with the expertise needed to make a meaningful impact in the field of technology management.</p> <p>In conclusion, Dino’s journey as a graduate student at Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember marks a significant milestone in his career. The skills and knowledge he acquires will not only prepare him for future challenges but will also empower him to be a leader in the world of technological innovation and business analytics.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="academic"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the ever-evolving world of technology and business, innovation and advanced knowledge have become crucial drivers of success. It is in this dynamic landscape that Dino has embarked on a thrilling new chapter in his life, beginning his journey as a graduate student at the prestigious Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember (ITS)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Staying Motivated at Work by Always Having Breakfast</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/family/2023/07/27/breakfast.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Staying Motivated at Work by Always Having Breakfast"/><published>2023-07-27T11:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-27T11:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/family/2023/07/27/breakfast</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/family/2023/07/27/breakfast.html"><![CDATA[<p>In our fast-paced world, work often takes precedence over everything else in our lives. With deadlines looming and endless tasks on our to-do lists, maintaining a high level of energy and motivation can be a real challenge. However, there’s one simple habit that can make a significant difference: starting your day with a nutritious breakfast. Here’s why having breakfast is essential for staying motivated at work.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/09-breakfast/dino-arla-breakfast-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/09-breakfast/dino-arla-breakfast-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/09-breakfast/dino-arla-breakfast-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/09-breakfast/dino-arla-breakfast-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/09-breakfast/dino-arla-breakfast-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/09-breakfast/dino-arla-breakfast-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/09-breakfast/dino-arla-breakfast-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/09-breakfast/dino-arla-breakfast-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Staying Motivated at Work by Always Having Breakfast </div> <h2 id="the-significance-of-breakfast">The Significance of Breakfast</h2> <p>Breakfast is often referred to as the most important meal of the day. After a long night of fasting, our bodies need fuel to kickstart the day. Eating a well-balanced breakfast provides the necessary nutrients and energy to keep us productive and focused.</p> <p>Studies have shown that individuals who eat breakfast tend to have better concentration, memory, and cognitive functions. This can lead to increased productivity and efficiency at work, allowing you to tackle tasks more effectively.</p> <h2 id="boosting-energy-and-mood">Boosting Energy and Mood</h2> <p>Skipping breakfast can leave you feeling sluggish and irritable, making it harder to stay motivated. On the other hand, having breakfast helps stabilize your blood sugar levels, which can prevent energy crashes later in the day.</p> <p>Including complex carbohydrates, protein, and healthy fats in your breakfast can provide sustained energy and improve your mood, making it easier to face the challenges of the workday with a positive attitude.</p> <h2 id="managing-a-long-commute">Managing a Long Commute</h2> <p>For many, like Dino who spends about an hour commuting from home to the office, having breakfast becomes even more crucial. The long distance can add stress and fatigue, but starting the day with a nutritious meal helps maintain energy levels during the commute and upon arrival at work.</p> <h2 id="encouraging-healthier-choices">Encouraging Healthier Choices</h2> <p>Starting the day with breakfast can set a precedence for making healthier food choices throughout the day. When you begin your day with healthy eating habits, you’re more likely to continue those habits, choosing nutritious snacks and meals that support your overall well-being.</p> <p>Additionally, having breakfast can prevent overeating later in the day, which often happens when people skip this vital meal. By maintaining a balanced diet, you’ll find it easier to keep your energy levels up and remain motivated at work.</p> <h2 id="tips-for-a-healthy-breakfast">Tips for a Healthy Breakfast</h2> <ol> <li>Plan Ahead: Prepare your breakfast the night before to save time in the morning.</li> <li>Balance Your Plate: Include whole grains, lean proteins, and fruits or vegetables in your breakfast.</li> <li>Stay Hydrated: Don’t forget to drink water or have a glass of fresh juice to start your day.</li> <li>Mindful Eating: Take time to enjoy your breakfast without distractions. Being mindful of what you eat can improve digestion and satisfaction.</li> </ol> <p>In conclusion, maintaining motivation at work starts with fueling your body appropriately each morning. By making breakfast a non-negotiable part of your routine, you’re setting yourself up for a day of productivity, energy, and positivity. So, keep that breakfast bowl ready and embrace the day with renewed vigor and enthusiasm!</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="family"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[With deadlines looming and endless tasks on our to-do lists, maintaining a high level of energy and motivation can be a real challenge. However, there’s one simple habit that can make a significant difference, starting your day with a nutritious breakfast. Here’s why having breakfast is essential for staying motivated at work.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Companions of PLN in Power Generation - Now Become a Proud Husbands and Fatherman</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/friendship/2023/07/22/companion-pln.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Companions of PLN in Power Generation - Now Become a Proud Husbands and Fatherman"/><published>2023-07-22T23:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-22T23:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/friendship/2023/07/22/companion-pln</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/friendship/2023/07/22/companion-pln.html"><![CDATA[<p>In the ever-evolving world of power generation, a group of young, spirited individuals embarked on a journey that would not only shape their careers but also their personal lives. These companions from PLN (Perusahaan Listrik Negara), Indonesia’s state electricity company, have grown together professionally and personally, transitioning from being fresh graduates to seasoned professionals, and now, loving husbands and proud fathers.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/08-companion-pln/dino-arla-companion-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> The Companions of PLN in Power Generation </div> <h2 id="the-beginnings">The Beginnings</h2> <p>The story of these comrades began in the bustling halls of PLN, where they met as new recruits eager to make a mark in the field of power generation. Their shared mission to ensure reliable electricity supply to millions of Indonesians forged a bond that transcended professional boundaries. Late-night shifts, challenging projects, and countless brainstorming sessions were the backdrop to their budding camaraderie.</p> <h2 id="the-journey-in-power-generation">The Journey in Power Generation</h2> <p>Working in power generation is no small feat. It demands technical expertise, resilience, and a commitment to continuous learning. These companions quickly adapted to the dynamic environment, supporting each other through the complexities of the job. They celebrated successes and consoled one another in the face of setbacks, learning invaluable lessons along the way.</p> <h2 id="from-colleagues-to-friends">From Colleagues to Friends</h2> <p>As time passed, their relationships deepened. What started as professional collaboration blossomed into genuine friendships. They shared not only career aspirations but also personal dreams and challenges. Weekend get-togethers became a norm, and soon, they were an integral part of each other’s lives outside of work.</p> <h2 id="the-next-chapter-marriage-and-parenthood">The Next Chapter: Marriage and Parenthood</h2> <p>Life took a beautiful turn when these companions found love and embarked on the journey of marriage. Their weddings were joyous occasions, attended by their PLN colleagues who had become more like family. As they transitioned into married life, they continued to support each other, now sharing advice on balancing work and personal responsibilities.</p> <p>The arrival of children marked another milestone in their lives. Parenthood brought its own set of challenges and joys, and these friends found new ways to connect, swapping stories about sleepless nights and first steps. They cherished the opportunity to watch their children grow, hopeful for a future where they could share the tales of their enduring friendship and professional journey.</p> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>Today, these companions of PLN, who once embarked on a journey in power generation, stand as exemplars of balance and perseverance. They have shown that it is possible to nurture both a successful career and a fulfilling family life. Their story is a testament to the power of friendship, unity, and shared experiences, reminding us that while the path to success is important, it is the companions we travel with that truly enrich our lives.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="friendship"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[These companions from PLN (Perusahaan Listrik Negara), Indonesia's state electricity company, have grown together professionally and personally, transitioning from being fresh graduates to seasoned professionals, and now, loving husbands and proud fathers.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Togetherness with the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/06/15/cikedung-p2tl.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Togetherness with the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team"/><published>2023-06-15T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-15T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/06/15/cikedung-p2tl</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/06/15/cikedung-p2tl.html"><![CDATA[<p>In the quaint district of Cikedung, a remarkable team of dedicated individuals is making a significant difference in the community. Led by the dynamic Dino Arla, who serves as the Commander of Energy Transactions, the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team works tirelessly to ensure that electricity usage in the area is both efficient and fair. But beyond their professional commitments, there exists a strong sense of camaraderie and togetherness among the team members that sets them apart.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-08-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-08-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-08-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-08.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-04-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-04-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-04-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-04.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team </div> <h2 id="fostering-a-family-like-atmosphere">Fostering a Family-Like Atmosphere</h2> <p>Under Dino Arla’s leadership, every individual in the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team is valued not only for their skills and contributions but also for their unique personalities. Dino has instilled a culture that fosters an environment more like a family than a workplace. Regular team-building activities, such as community outings and participation in local events, help strengthen the bonds between members. Through these activities, team members learn to trust and rely on each other, which is crucial in their line of work.</p> <h2 id="bringing-the-community-together">Bringing the Community Together</h2> <p>The PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team, guided by Dino’s strategic vision, is deeply integrated into the community. They actively engage with locals to educate them about electricity usage and safety. These interactions are not just formalities but are opportunities for the team to connect with residents on a personal level. This approach, championed by Dino, has created a strong rapport between the team and the community, making their enforcement efforts more effective and welcomed.</p> <h2 id="overcoming-challenges-together">Overcoming Challenges Together</h2> <p>The job of ensuring proper electricity usage is not without its challenges. Under Dino Arla’s capable supervision, the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team often faces difficult situations, such as dealing with illegal electricity connections or addressing power shortages. However, the sense of unity among the team members allows them to face these challenges head-on. They support each other through thick and thin, celebrating successes and learning from setbacks together.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-03-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-03-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-03-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-03.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team - Meeting and Evaluation </div> <h2 id="significant-financial-impact">Significant Financial Impact</h2> <p>The dedication and efficiency of the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team have significantly contributed to the recovery and saving of company income, exceeding 4 billion rupiahs. This remarkable achievement underscores the team’s effectiveness in combating electricity misuse and optimizing energy distribution.</p> <h2 id="the-impact-of-togetherness">The Impact of Togetherness</h2> <p>The togetherness of the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team, led by Dino Arla, has had a profound impact on both their work and their lives. It has improved their effectiveness in ensuring proper electricity usage and has contributed to a positive work environment that prioritizes well-being and collaboration. This unity, cultivated by Dino, is reflected in their interactions with the community and is a key factor in the team’s success.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-05-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-05-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-05-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-05.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-06-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-06-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-06-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-06.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-07-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-07-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-07-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/07-ckd-p2tl/dino-arla-ckd-p2tl-07.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team </div> <p>In conclusion, with Dino Arla at the helm, the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team stands as a model of how teamwork and togetherness can lead to success and satisfaction in professional endeavors. Their dedication to their work and each other is a testament to the power of unity and community spirit.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="pln"/><category term="cikedung"/><category term="indramayu"/><category term="acceleraterenewableenergy"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Led by the dynamic Dino Arla, who serves as the Commander of Energy Transactions, the PLN Cikedung Electricity Usage Enforcement Team works tirelessly to ensure that electricity usage in the area is both efficient and fair.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Enhancing Customer Experience - PLN Cikedung’s Service Connection Team</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/06/14/cikedung-yanbung.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Enhancing Customer Experience - PLN Cikedung’s Service Connection Team"/><published>2023-06-14T15:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-14T15:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/06/14/cikedung-yanbung</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/06/14/cikedung-yanbung.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2> <p>The utility sector is a crucial backbone of modern society, providing essential services that power our homes, businesses, and industries. In Indonesia, PLN (Perusahaan Listrik Negara) plays a vital role in ensuring that electricity reaches every corner of the country. Today, we’re taking a closer look at the “Tim Pelayanan Penyambungan” or “Service Connection Team” in Cikedung, a dedicated unit that has been making significant strides in improving customer experience and satisfaction.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> PLN Cikedung Service Connection Team </div> <h2 id="who-is-the-service-connection-team">Who is the Service Connection Team?</h2> <p>The Service Connection Team of PLN Cikedung is a specialized group of skilled professionals responsible for overseeing and executing the process of connecting new electricity installations. This team manages everything from initial customer inquiries to the final installation, ensuring a seamless experience for customers who need to connect to the power grid.</p> <h2 id="key-functions-of-the-team">Key Functions of the Team</h2> <ol> <li>Customer Consultation and Support</li> <li>The team serves as the first point of contact for customers looking to connect their premises to the electricity supply. They provide comprehensive consultations, offering guidance on the application process, required documentation, and any relevant regulations or tariffs.</li> <li>Site Assessment and Planning</li> <li>Before installation, the team conducts thorough site assessments to determine the specific requirements for each connection. This involves evaluating the infrastructure, identifying potential challenges, and developing a tailored plan to ensure a smooth and efficient installation process.</li> <li>Installation and Quality Assurance</li> <li>Once the planning phase is complete, the team proceeds with the installation. Using state-of-the-art equipment and adhering to strict safety standards, they ensure that all connections are made accurately and securely. After installation, they perform rigorous quality checks to confirm that the service meets all operational and safety standards.</li> </ol> <h2 id="commitment-to-customer-satisfaction">Commitment to Customer Satisfaction</h2> <p>One of the standout attributes of the Service Connection Team is their unwavering commitment to customer satisfaction. They prioritize clear communication and responsiveness, keeping customers informed at every stage of the process and addressing any concerns promptly. Their customer-centric approach has earned them a reputation for reliability and trustworthiness in the Cikedung area.</p> <h2 id="challenges-and-innovations">Challenges and Innovations</h2> <p>Like any service-oriented team, the PLN Cikedung Service Connection Team faces challenges, such as navigating complex field environments and managing high customer demands. However, they continually strive to innovate and improve their processes. By leveraging technology, such as digital platforms for tracking and managing customer data, they enhance efficiency and accuracy in service delivery.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-03-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-03-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-03-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/06-ckd-yanbung/dino-arla-ckd-yanbung-03.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> PLN Cikedung Service Connection Team </div> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>The PLN Cikedung Service Connection Team exemplifies dedication and innovation in the electricity sector. By focusing on customer needs and embracing modern technology, they not only improve connectivity but also contribute to the broader goal of electrifying every corner of Indonesia. Their work ensures that communities and businesses can thrive with reliable and efficient access to electricity, powering progress and development in the region.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="pln"/><category term="cikedung"/><category term="indramayu"/><category term="acceleraterenewableenergy"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we’re taking a closer look at the Tim Pelayanan Penyambungan or Service Connection Team in PLN Cikedung, a dedicated unit that has been making significant strides in improving customer experience and satisfaction.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcoming Our New Manager at PLN Cikedung - A new era of teamwork, sustainability, and innovation</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/06/10/cikedung-new-manager.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcoming Our New Manager at PLN Cikedung - A new era of teamwork, sustainability, and innovation"/><published>2023-06-10T14:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-10T14:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/06/10/cikedung-new-manager</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/06/10/cikedung-new-manager.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are thrilled to announce a fresh chapter in our journey at PLN Cikedung with the appointment of our new Manager and Leader, Lukman Ismail. As of June 2023, Lukman Ismail will be spearheading our operations, bringing a wealth of knowledge and experience to our team.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/05-new-manager/dino-arla-ckd-manager-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/05-new-manager/dino-arla-ckd-manager-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/05-new-manager/dino-arla-ckd-manager-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/05-new-manager/dino-arla-ckd-manager-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/05-new-manager/dino-arla-ckd-manager-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/05-new-manager/dino-arla-ckd-manager-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/05-new-manager/dino-arla-ckd-manager-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/05-new-manager/dino-arla-ckd-manager-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> PLN Cikedung New Squad of June 2023 </div> <h2 id="a-brief-history-of-pln-cikedung">A Brief History of PLN Cikedung</h2> <p>PLN Cikedung has been a cornerstone in the energy sector since its establishment in 2019. Over the years, we have evolved to become one of the leading power distribution companies in the region, renowned for our commitment to providing reliable and sustainable energy solutions.</p> <p>Our journey began with a modest start, serving a small community and steadily growing our infrastructure and capacity. With a focus on innovation and customer service, PLN Cikedung expanded its reach and capabilities, integrating advanced technologies that set new standards in power distribution and management.</p> <h2 id="a-new-era-of-leadership">A New Era of Leadership</h2> <p>Lukman Ismail joins us with over 15 years of experience in the energy sector, specializing in technical of energy distribution. His previous roles include supervisor of technical both ULP and UP3, where he successfully led projects that improved operational efficiency and customer satisfaction.</p> <p>His proven track record in leadership and innovation makes him an ideal fit for PLN Cikedung. Lukman Ismail is committed to driving our company forward, embracing new opportunities, and tackling challenges with a strategic and visionary approach.</p> <h2 id="vision-for-pln-cikedung">Vision for PLN Cikedung</h2> <p>In his inaugural address, Lukman Ismail emphasized the importance of teamwork, sustainability, and innovation. His vision for PLN Cikedung is centered around enhancing our service quality, expanding our renewable energy capabilities, and fostering a culture of continuous improvement.</p> <p>Under Lukman Ismail’s leadership, we are excited to explore new technologies and methodologies that align with the global shift towards sustainable energy solutions. His focus on employee development and community engagement ensures that PLN Cikedung not only meets but exceeds the expectations of our stakeholders.</p> <h2 id="looking-ahead">Looking Ahead</h2> <p>The future is bright at PLN Cikedung, and we are confident that with Lukman Ismail at the helm, we will achieve new milestones and set benchmarks in the industry. We invite all our partners, employees, and customers to join us in welcoming Lukman Ismail and to look forward to what promises to be an exciting and transformative era for our organization.</p> <p>Stay tuned for more updates and initiatives as we embark on this new journey together. Welcome aboard, Lukman Ismail!</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="pln"/><category term="cikedung"/><category term="indramayu"/><category term="acceleraterenewableenergy"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are thrilled to announce a fresh chapter in our journey at PLN Cikedung with the appointment of our new Manager and Leader, Lukman Ismail. As of June 2023, Lukman Ismail will be spearheading our operations, bringing a wealth of knowledge and experience to our team.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PLN Cikedung Squad Year 2023 - A Year of Power and Progress</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/05/10/cikedung-squad.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PLN Cikedung Squad Year 2023 - A Year of Power and Progress"/><published>2023-05-10T12:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-10T12:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/05/10/cikedung-squad</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/pln/2023/05/10/cikedung-squad.html"><![CDATA[<p>The year 2023 has been a remarkable one for the PLN Cikedung squad, a dedicated unit of the State Electricity Company of Indonesia (PLN) located in Indramayu. With the responsibility of serving over 70,000 customers, they have shown exceptional commitment and innovation in meeting the community’s electricity needs.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> PLN Cikedung Squad Year 2023 </div> <h2 id="customer-centric-focus">Customer-Centric Focus</h2> <p>The PLN Cikedung squad has always prioritized customer satisfaction. This year, they have implemented several initiatives to enhance customer service, including the introduction of a new online portal that allows customers to report outages and pay bills conveniently. These improvements have not only increased efficiency but also strengthened the trust between PLN Cikedung and its customers.</p> <h2 id="technological-advancements">Technological Advancements</h2> <p>In 2023, the Cikedung team embraced technological advancements to improve the reliability and efficiency of their services. With the integration of smart grid technology, the squad has been able to better manage electricity distribution, quickly responding to demand fluctuations and minimizing power outages. This transition has paved the way for more sustainable and reliable power solutions.</p> <h2 id="community-engagement">Community Engagement</h2> <p>Understanding the importance of community involvement, PLN Cikedung has engaged in various community outreach programs. These initiatives aimed at educating the public about energy conservation and safety have received positive feedback. By fostering a sense of community responsibility, PLN Cikedung has helped promote sustainable energy practices among its customer base.</p> <h2 id="environmental-responsibility">Environmental Responsibility</h2> <p>With a growing emphasis on sustainability, the PLN Cikedung squad has also been committed to reducing their environmental footprint. Through initiatives such as integrating renewable energy sources and promoting energy efficiency, they are not only contributing to a greener planet but also setting an example for others in the industry.</p> <h2 id="challenges-and-triumphs">Challenges and Triumphs</h2> <p>Despite facing challenges such as infrastructure demands and increasing energy consumption, the PLN Cikedung squad has demonstrated resilience and adaptability. Their ability to overcome obstacles and deliver on their promises has been a testament to their dedication and hard work.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-03-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-03-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-03-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/04-cikedung-squad/dino-arla-ckd-squad-03.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> PLN Cikedung Squad Year 2023 </div> <p>In conclusion, the year 2023 has been a transformative year for the PLN Cikedung squad. Through innovation, dedication, and community engagement, they have not only upheld their reputation but also set new benchmarks for the future. As they move forward, the PLN Cikedung squad continues to be a beacon of progress in the field of electricity distribution, serving as a powerful example for others to follow.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="pln"/><category term="cikedung"/><category term="indramayu"/><category term="acceleraterenewableenergy"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The year 2023 has been a remarkable one for the PLN Cikedung squad, a dedicated unit of the State Electricity Company of Indonesia (PLN) located in Indramayu. With the responsibility of serving over 70,000 customers, they have shown exceptional commitment and innovation in meeting the community's electricity needs.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reuniting with Old Friends - PLN Batch 7 year 2013 (King Solomon) Gathering for Eid al-Fitr 1444 H</title><link href="https://dinoarla.com/friendship/2023/04/27/reuniting-with-old-friends.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reuniting with Old Friends - PLN Batch 7 year 2013 (King Solomon) Gathering for Eid al-Fitr 1444 H"/><published>2023-04-27T12:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-27T12:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dinoarla.com/friendship/2023/04/27/reuniting-with-old-friends</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dinoarla.com/friendship/2023/04/27/reuniting-with-old-friends.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2> <p>Eid al-Fitr, a significant celebration for Muslims around the world, transcends religious rites, symbolizing unity, forgiveness, and the rekindling of relationships. This year, the spirit of Eid brought us together with our cherished friends from “PLN Batch 7 year 2013 (King Solomon)”, marking a joyful reunion filled with laughter and nostalgia.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-02-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-02-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-02-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-02.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Dino and his family celebrate Eid al-Fitr 1444 H with PLN Batch 7 year 2013 (King Solomon) </div> <h2 id="a-walk-down-memory-lane">A Walk Down Memory Lane</h2> <p>The gathering took place at the home of one of our colleagues, a cozy haven that was soon filled with familiar faces and the warm embrace of friendship. As we reminisced about our formative years in PLN, it was incredible to see how far we have come since our days in the technical training program, affectionately known as “PLN Angkatan 7 Jalur Pelaksana”.</p> <p>The conversations flowed as freely as the delectable Eid treats. Stories of our early days in the field, the successes, the challenges, and the bonds we forged through hard work and shared experiences, were recounted with enthusiasm and fondness. Each tale told was a reminder of the journey we had embarked on together and the shared dreams we continue to pursue. Without realizing it, we have all now become parents.</p> <h2 id="parenting-moments">Parenting Moments</h2> <p>One of the most endearing highlights of the reunion was the presence of our children, who quickly became the stars of the event. As the adults caught up, the little ones mingled effortlessly, playing games and forming friendships of their own, a new generation of bonds taking shape. At one point, the living room was transformed into an impromptu play area, filled with laughter and the sounds of tiny footsteps running around.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-01-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-01-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-01-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-01.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-04-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-04-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-04-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-04.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Eid Al-Fitr parenting moments with PLN Batch 7 year 2013 (King Solomon) </div> <p>A particularly memorable moment was when two of the kids decided to host a “talent show,” showcasing their unique skills. Their enthusiasm and creativity left everyone in stitches and served as a charming reminder of the joys of parenthood we now share. Another touching scene unfolded when a child, eager to demonstrate their reading skills, gathered a small audience to listen. It was heartwarming to see the pride in their parents’ eyes, a universal moment every parent cherishes.</p> <h2 id="unity-and-gratitude">Unity and Gratitude</h2> <p>In addition to reliving past memories, the gathering was an opportunity to express gratitude for the support and camaraderie that have helped us navigate our careers and personal lives. It was a time to acknowledge the growth and achievements of our peers, celebrate our shared heritage, and strengthen the bonds that unite us.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-03-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-03-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-03-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/02-reuniting-old-friends/dino-arla-reuniting-old-friends-2023-03.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Togetherness of King Solomon Founders </div> <h2 id="looking-forward">Looking Forward</h2> <p>As we look to the future, the reunion reminded us of the importance of maintaining relationships and the powerful impact they have on our lives. We left with a renewed sense of connection and the promise to meet again, ensuring that the spirit of “Silaturahmi” continues to thrive within our PLN family.</p> <p>Eid al-Fitr 1444 H has been a truly enriching experience, one that reinforced the value of friendship and community, and highlighted the enduring strength of our bonds. We are grateful for the memories shared, and eagerly look forward to creating new ones in the years to come.</p>]]></content><author><name>Dino Arla</name></author><category term="friendship"/><category term="personal"/><category term="friendship"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This year, the spirit of Eid brought us together with our cherished friends from PLN Batch 7 year 2013 (King Solomon), marking a joyful reunion filled with laughter and nostalgia.]]></summary></entry></feed>